[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "Question_id": 1,
    "question": "What are the values of family in your country?",
    "answer": "That's a really important question. First of all, I believe that family values don't differ from country to country and please allow me to say that they should be the same throughout the world. As far as I’m concerned, the most important values of a family are the moral values, which enable people to draw plausible distinctions between right and wrong, good and bad, true and false. The lessons learned from the family are invaluable throughout our life. A family is the most important group that makes life worth living.\n\nFurthermore, family values are vital in making decisions and can be obtained by personal and life experiences with close relationships with family members. To be more specific, some examples could be: being honest and trustworthy, courageous and patient, taking up responsibilities as well as adding values to the world are the norms of our family and society. A family is utterly important and we stand for our family members no matter what. Thus 'family comes first' is the morality everyone in our country believes in. We also consider a family as the unit of a society or a country and bonding, relationship, trustworthiness, helpfulness are lessons which come with the close family ties."
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "Question_id": 1,
    "question": "How family bonding is necessary for happiness in life?",
    "answer": "Our parents are the reason for our existence and with them, we get a family. Parents are the persons we see and rely on when we open our eyes for the first time. Moreover, parents are the primary educator and they teach their children how to develop confidence, social skills, morals, values and views in life. Since they are the base of our family, closeness in a family leads people to have an intrinsically fulfilling and flourishing life.\n\nThis can be justified by the fact that children who enjoy strong family bonding tend to be happier and mentally healthier than those who are in a dysfunctional family environment."
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "Question_id": 1,
    "question": "What type of family do you like? Nuclear family or joint family?",
    "answer": "That’s really an interesting question! A nuclear family is preferable to me than a joint family. The reason for my preference is perhaps because I grew up in a nuclear family and it was a pleasant memory for me. Besides, in a nuclear family, the couple and their children have a stronger relationship. Fighting and quarrel are rare in nuclear families.\n\nOn the other hand, the second type of family is the extended family or joint family and includes grandparents, uncles, aunts, cousins and so on. I prefer a quiet environment than a noisy one. In a joint family, this is unlikely to happen and people often do not have sufficient privacy. Therefore, I strongly believe that a family only with mum, dad and siblings would work better for me."
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "Question_id": 1,
    "question": "How family value and bonding have changed over the last decade?",
    "answer": "Unfortunately, the sacred notion of a family has lost its meaning to a certain extent in the last ten years. People don’t invest in feelings anymore and don’t retreat as well. Nowadays quarrels between couples are a frequent occurrence and because women are financially independent, they don’t step back like they did many years ago. Moreover, a principal cause that has led to this situation is the overreliance on the Internet. When family members have some spare time they prefer to consume it by going online instead of having some family conversations. I would jump to the conclusion that people who decide to create a family should let go their ego and in difficult times they should also think that their children want their parents to be happy and together."
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "Question_id": 2,
    "question": "Which one is better: home-made food or food from a restaurant?",
    "answer": "This question is really enticing. It seems to me that home-made food is healthier; of course, because you are completely responsible for its preparation and you know exactly the ingredients that are included. For example, you are aware of the quantity of salt, olive oil, sugar, pepper et cetera.\n\nOn the other hand, the food at restaurants is undoubtedly more delicious and satiating, but it isn't as wholesome as the former. These types of food are high in saturated fats and oils and they aren't easily digestible. So I would argue that restaurant food is tastier but the home-made food is healthier. Moreover, food in restaurants is expensive while home-made food is not."
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "Question_id": 2,
    "question": "What traditional food do you have in your country?",
    "answer": "For the last three years I have been living in the UK but I am a native of Greece so I would like to talk about Greek traditional foods. Greek cuisine is renowned worldwide and not without a reason. First and foremost we have the famous Greek souvlaki combined with tzatziki. This is the food that anyone who comes to Greece wants to taste. Going further, I can think of Greek mousakas which is a really tasty dish and it consists of potatoes, eggplants, minced beef and cream. Similar to mousakas, pastitsio is equally delicious with some variations. There are many other types of food, but I think that those I have already mentioned are the ''landmark'' of the Greek diet."
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "Question_id": 2,
    "question": "What types of food tourists in your city prefer?",
    "answer": "The types of food tourists in Greece try and enjoy vary greatly. Some tourists come here to enjoy traditional food like Barbouni, Dolmades, Kokoretsi and Gigandes. Some try fast-food and like to visit a food court that has brands like KFC or McDonald's. Finally, many solely prefer vegan items like Fava, Spanakopita and Skordalia. \n\nI have even seen some tourists who try anything they find interesting and young tourists mostly fall into this category."
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "Question_id": 3,
    "question": "How often do you read books?",
    "answer": "Unfortunately, I don't read books very often. When I was younger, my mom used to tell me stories from different books so this is the reason that I am aware of the fairytales. I read 'Twilight' by Stephenie Meyer when I was 15 years old and the motivation to do that was the movie with the same name which was released in 2008. From another perspective, though, I read almost all of my books when I was at university but I was forced to do that. So I would come to the conclusion that I don't read books in my free time but only when I have to.\n\nTip: You can either say that you don't or you do read books. If you are in the first category refer to the reasons why you don't do that. For example, you can say that you don't have time, many interesting books are expensive, you can't read online books because it's tiring and anything else comes to your mind.\n\nIf you are in the second category, just think of the kinds of books you have read and try to describe them in a few words. You can also include your university books."
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "Question_id": 3,
    "question": "How books can impact on a man's life?",
    "answer": "Books are good sources of knowledge and they actually enlighten us. Reading a book is a really good and helpful way whenever you are bored or stressed out. It is preferable to me reading a book than surfing the internet. Going further, in this way people can develop their imagination and nurture their mind and thinking skills. Moreover, there is a possibility for someone to change their view about specific things such as religious issues, gender parity, culture and so on and become more open-minded by reading books. For instance, somebody who isn't romantic may change his opinion after reading a book with a romantic story or someone who is narrow-minded and biassed may change their attitude. Finally, it's a good and effective way to practice a foreign language and this is something I did before coming to England."
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "Question_id": 3,
    "question": "Name some of the famous writers of your country?",
    "answer": "One of the most famous English writers is JK Rowling, the author of the Harry Potter fantasy series. Her books have gained worldwide attention, won multiple awards, and were sold more than 400 million copies so far. John Milton whose poetry has been seen as the perfect poetic expression in the English language for four centuries is also from my country. Agatha Christie who is reputably known throughout the world as the \"Queen of Crime\" and Samuel Johnson who is known as 'arguably the most distinguished man of letters in English history' are only some of the many meritorious English authors.\n\nTip: You can talk about a/few writer(s) of your own country who is successful and well-known even worldwide. They might be contemporary writers or might be from past centuries."
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "Question_id": 3,
    "question": "Have you ever thought about writing a book?",
    "answer": "To be honest I haven't. My writing skill isn't so good, so if I had decided to do something like that it would have been a moderate work. In fact, I wouldn't want that because I am a perfectionist. In addition, my imagination isn't that vivid to create a story myself so I would jump to the conclusion that I am not the proper person for this activity. Besides, my favourite types of books are biographies so this is the only plot that I could have written. However, I prefer sharing my personal stories and experiences with my family and friends in verbal form than written form.\n\nTip: You can also give a semi-negative answer by saying that you haven't written a book but you would like to and give examples and your idea about the story. You can also say that you have thought about writing a book and refer to its content. Finally, you can say that you have written a book if so give details when you wrote it, what was the story and how you were inspired to write this book."
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "Question_id": 3,
    "question": "How reading books is different from watching movies?",
    "answer": "It is quite different indeed! While reading a book you can imagine the characters and the scenes you are reading about and adjust them to your desires. Everyone makes an image of the main characters' outer appearance, inner traits and so on and personally when I read a book I have a specific actor or actress in my mind. So, I would say that books give someone the chance to make stories based on their personality.\n\nMovies, on the other hand, have some standards. There is the visual element which is absent in books and it can be either good or bad because in some cases watching a movie is much better than reading a book but the opposite can happen as well. Personally, I have seen movies having read the books before and some of them weren't as good as I expected."
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "Question_id": 4,
    "question": "What is the importance of travelling?",
    "answer": "That's an interesting and important question actually. Firstly, travelling allows us to meet new people, gather first-hand experiences and have new experiences. Secondly, knowledge about culture, history and overall civilisation is enhanced by travelling and by making new acquaintances people can swap opinions and values, let go of false beliefs and become more broad-minded and less regressive. Lastly, travelling cultivates tolerance and understanding, breaks the barriers of the mind, removes the existing prejudices and results in positive changes in attitudes by reminding everyone that we are all the same and we should treat each other with respect and compassion."
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "Question_id": 4,
    "question": "What type of places do you recommend people to visit on vacation?",
    "answer": "As far as I'm concerned, for summer vacation I would definitely suggest that people should go to maritime areas so that they can relax, swim, and enjoy their free time. In other seasons, of course, it depends on people's personality, but I would recommend hillbilly areas. In spring, for example, going to a place and enjoying nature is a very good outlet and helps people relax and oxygenate their brain. Furthermore, in winter, areas with mountains and hills are the best options and they can go skiing and climbing. As mentioned, it is a matter of character and preference, but from my point of view, the above suggestions would make everyone enjoy the vacation."
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "Question_id": 4,
    "question": "Where do you want to visit in the future? Why?",
    "answer": "I want to travel around the world and visit many countries, but since I was a child I have been dreaming to visit America one day. I used to and still do watch American TV series and movies and I really like different things there. For example, I always wanted to see the Statue of Liberty and go to the Brooklyn Bridge. I adore the way people live in that country and the architecture of different houses as well, especially those in the suburbs. Of course, New York, the city that never sleeps, is my main aim, but I would also like to investigate other cities and places. To conclude, I would visit many museums and historic places as well as the White House in the United States. I would also like to see the seven modern wonders of the world.\n\nTips: America is my personal preference and I have mentioned some of the reasons why I would like to go there. You can mention the same country and add some other details or you can say about other countries. You can also mention a destination in your own country that you have never been to. Just justify your choice."
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "Question_id": 5,
    "question": "How long have you been using the Internet?",
    "answer": "I have been using the Internet since I bought my first personal computer in 2007. At first, I didn't know how to use it properly but as time went by I became aware of it. I use it constantly every day either for studies and work or for entertainment. I check my e-mails, read the news, watch movies and TV series, listen to music and so on. It's instantly accessible and I can find a massive amount of information on various topics such as health issues, environmental, economy, sports, education et cetera. I have become really dependent on that and I consume almost all of my spare time surfing the internet."
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "Question_id": 5,
    "question": "How the Internet has changed our lifestyle?",
    "answer": "This is a really controversial issue. On the one hand, the Internet has made our lives better and simpler as everyone nowadays seems to be moving online. It provides reliable and accurate information on many topics. It is user-friendly because you can find anything you need by just sitting on a chair rather than going to a library and of course it has made communication much easier and faster as it connects people across the globe. Furthermore, it results in developing our cognitive skills because we can gain or even expand our existing knowledge and this knowledge can be shared instantly.\n\nOn the other hand, the Internet has led to a kind of addiction and it declines the ability to interact and socialise. This leads to isolation and feelings of loneliness because we deprive of social interaction. Last but not least, the Internet can be risky in some cases, especially for kids, and for online transactions. Hacking, identity theft, and online crimes are some common drawbacks of the Internet.\n\nTips:\nPositive sides it fosters communication around the world, helps people make more friends, creates opportunities for business and e-commerce, offer online shopping at better prices, fosters tolerance and understanding, creates positive changes in attitudes, brings information at our finger tap, makes business transactions easier and helps in learning things in a better and efficient way.\n\nNegative sides: Widespread use of the Internet leads to isolation. Moreover, identity theft, hacking, the spread of malware & virus are unwanted. Finally, the dependency on the Internet kills our social skill."
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "Question_id": 5,
    "question": "What would be the possible uses of the Internet in the future?",
    "answer": "My personal opinion is that driving is an activity that will be controlled entirely by the Internet in the future. Furthermore, it will be able to trace any kind of shortages of necessary goods in our houses, for example, if we run out of sugar, coffee, fruits and vegetables etc., the Internet will place online orders for those items automatically. It will have a predominant role in the field of medicine as well by making all kinds of surgeries and check-ups and doctors will only have to press a button. Another use that comes to my mind is in the universities. In the next twenty years or so, lectures will only be online and every student will have to attend university from their own personal computer. Moreover, people will primarily communicate using the Internet, landlines and cell phone networks would no longer be required. Finally, more interactive software and websites would be available that would connect the world data and would serve to the users."
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "Question_id": 6,
    "question": "What should be done to reduce road accidents?",
    "answer": "In my opinion, awareness and responsibility are the two important elements to tackle this crucial matter. In particular, by raising awareness people will become well-informed and it might lead to the decline of road accidents. This could occur with the intervention by governing bodies, family, school and even campaigners. Accountability is also an essential characteristic. There are many cases, especially in Europe, when people go out and drink and after that, they drive back home on their own. Terrible accidents can happen under the influence of alcohol and we should underline that most of the time not only drunk drivers are getting killed but also sober drivers and innocent people are becoming victims who are in the wrong place at the wrong time.\n\nApart from that, the traffic system should be improved and the accident-prone roads should be reconstructed. Driving offences should be taken seriously and rigid tests and checking should be in place before giving someone a driving license."
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "Question_id": 6,
    "question": "Who should be responsible for the accidents?",
    "answer": "First and foremost, drivers have a great responsibility for any accident. Many factors such as alcohol, fake driving license, excessive speed, and lack of road safety contribute to the dramatic increase in road accidents. However, drivers are aware of these considerations so there is a matter of irresponsibility and whoever drives a car should be more responsible. In addition, parents play an important role as well, because they allow their children to drive despite the fact that they're underage and incapable of driving safely and consciously. Furthermore, there are some cases where accidents are caused by a faulty mechanism of cars. These cases aren't that common, but when it happens, the fatal is inevitable. So car manufacturers and distributors in some cases should be responsible as well."
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "Question_id": 6,
    "question": "What damages do you think occurs when an accident takes place?",
    "answer": "The most dangerous thing that happens in an accident is the loss of human lives. Due to unpleasant and unexpected accidents, many people pass away and this is the most terrible thing that could happen. Going further, the victims of road accidents often suffer minor or heavy injuries and the latter entails a long time of hospitalisation, with potential permanent damages. Vehicle damage is a further loss, as in most cases cars, motorcycles and all the other vehicles involved, end up completely mangled. Furthermore, the family members of the victims suffer from unbearable losses and the outcome often brings catastrophe to those family members."
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "Question_id": 7,
    "question": "Why childhood is important?",
    "answer": "As far as I'm concerned, childhood is the purest and happiest period of human life without any concerns, stress and wickedness. Every child is carefree, and two things that matter to them are playing and enjoying life. In addition, as youngsters are fluid and flexible in the way they approach things, everyone, especially parents, should spend constructive times with them because this is the period of life for learning and absorbing things in order to form their character and personality. More precisely, longitudinal research has shown that a person's successes, health and emotional wellbeing have their roots in early childhood.\n\nChildhood experiences define the way we behave and react in certain circumstances in later stages in our lives and our cognitive developments occur faster at that time. Childhood is a magical stage in our lives and has immense importance for the later stages of our lives."
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "Question_id": 7,
    "question": "How did you spend your childhood?",
    "answer": "I spent my childhood by playing most of the time and then\nbeing with my family and friends. I had many friends and we used to gather and play in our yards, especially hide and seek. I remember I didn't like the fact that I always got caught by my friends. When I was at home, though, I did the drawing, painting and dancing most the time. So, I would say that I really enjoyed my childhood and the most vivid thing that I still remember is my mother begging me to complete my homework. My parents were so caring and loving and I always loved to visit different places with them.\n\nTip: You can talk about your childhood by mentioning your hobbies, your school, siblings, friends or even pleasant or unpleasant situations you had."
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "Question_id": 7,
    "question": "Who was your childhood hero? Did you want to be like him/her?",
    "answer": "When I was a child my hero was the Superman. As I can remember, there was a TV series called 'Smallville' and the leading character in this TV series was a teenage boy whose name was Clark Kent. Clark was adopted and he had superhuman's powers and I was entirely surprised by that because he was saving people all the time using his power. But as a little kid, the thing that impressed me the most was that he wasn't only saving good people but also the bad one who tried to hurt him and his beloved ones. Although he was my hero, I didn't want to be like him but like his girlfriend, Lana Lang, you know this is natural for a girl of my age. After this show, I always wanted to have a superhero in my life and Superman was an indispensable part of my early childhood.\n\nTip: Mention your own hero and describe him/her and his/her achievements. If you didn't have any heroes, you can just say about common heroes such as Superman, Batman, Spiderman or even your parents and relatives. Just tell the examiner the reason why he or she was your hero and why you wanted to be like him/her."
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "Question_id": 8,
    "question": "How does a study room help a student?",
    "answer": "The most important aspect of having a separate study room is that it's quiet and personal. It gives a nice environment for studying and preparing for the exam. People can be totally isolated in their study rooms and can concentrate on what they want to do as they aren't distracted by others. A study room is the most suitable places for a student to study. Moreover, they can access the Internet, read or write, allocate their time in study and take rest whenever they want. This is not possible in other places. Therefore, a study room can lead to a more effective and constructive way of studying and offer an even easier way of understanding and assimilating new information and knowledge. Finally, a student can be totally himself whenever he is in his study room without worrying about what others would think about him."
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "Question_id": 8,
    "question": "Do you like to study? What type of books do you read?",
    "answer": "I love to read books-  be it a reference book, novel, biography or anything else that attracts me. Sometimes reading for an exam is a bit monotonous, but the outcome is great as it enhances my knowledge. Since I have already completed my graduation, I mostly read books that seem interesting to me. This includes fiction, biography, history and reference books. I am an active member of Goodreads - a website of an extensive user-populated database of books, annotations, and reviews. This website is a great source for picking up books to read. Besides I maintain a technology-related blog and for updating this blog, I need to read different articles and posts online.   \n  \nThe truth is that I don't like the process of studying but the outcome. When the time comes and I really have to study, I'm completely bored and sleepy. But as time goes by, I discover that I am equipped with the rudimentary knowledge that is necessary not only for my studies but also for my future career and life. Now that I've graduated from university, I really enjoy reading books from my last semester and especially those related to businesses. As becoming a business consultant is my dream and I'm very close to achieving that, I am motivated to spend some of my free time reading books about enterprises and gaining significant and useful knowledge."
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "Question_id": 8,
    "question": "Which one do you prefer - reading or travelling? Why?",
    "answer": "It's an interesting question and a bit difficult for me to answer as both pastimes are not only entertaining but also important in people's life. Reading can help someone acquire knowledge, enhance skills and competencies and of course stimulate our mind. Books are unparalleled in creating enlightened citizens in society.  \n\nTravelling, on the other hand, broadens our horizons, allows us to make new acquaintances and meet people from around the world. In addition to this, we can become knowledgeable about a country's history, customs and culture by travelling and this results in becoming a more broad-minded and less regressive person. It is indeed a tough call for me to decide my preference between these two! However, if I have to, I would say that travelling is a bit more preferable to reading because it offers me a chance to witness things and events that I never want to miss.\n\nTips: You can say that you prefer one of the two options or even both. You have to explain the reasons for your choice and it would be good to tell why you don't like the other one."
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "Question_id": 9,
    "question": "Do you think that gift-giving will play an important role in daily life in the future? Why?",
    "answer": "It seems to me that this is a bit ambiguous. More precisely, present giving is something that occurs in special events, for example, at birthdays, festivals, anniversaries, wedding, graduation day, on name days, when someone visits others and so on. I don't think that there are many people around the world who give presents to their loved ones or to friends on a daily basis. Furthermore, with regards to the future, I am of the opinion that giving gifts won't have a special role in everyday life either because, as I said earlier, presents are given when something important happens. However, there is no doubt that present giving plays an important role in our relationship and that will always remain the same."
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "Question_id": 9,
    "question": "Compare the gifts which people have received 10 years ago to the gifts that people now are receiving? What's the difference between them?",
    "answer": "To answer this question we have to go back to the past and think of the types of presents we gave and received. Despite my young age, I have some memories of such presents that my family and relatives gave me. I would say that in the past, specifically 10 years ago, the types of gifts exchanged were primarily clothes, toys, household appliances and books. Apart from the fact that they weren't related to technology, they were also significantly important, educational and in most cases and most of the time expensive. Nowadays, presents are more symbolic than substantial or useful. People these days often give and receive technology-related gifts which were quite rare in the past. To illustrate, the important gifts that I received on my last birthday were perfumes and a laptop. Of course, gifts items in all decades do not remain the same. It will change for sure after ten years. The love and good wishes behind a gift are more important than the item itself."
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "Question_id": 9,
    "question": "Do you think that the brand name is very important for sales?",
    "answer": "I believe that the brand name really matters and it affects the sales volume of a product. Most companies spend a huge amount of money on branding in order to make the product or service famous. We could say that branding is an enterprise itself because it constitutes an amazingly important part of the company and its viability. As branding is a core aspect of a company, brand managers try to acquire customers and maintain relationships with them. Moreover, through advertising, media exposure and celebrity endorsement sales are on the rise most of the time for popular brands.  \n\nPersonally, I would spend more money to purchase a branded product. Hence I am quite positive that brand name is important for sales."
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "Question_id": 10,
    "question": "What do you think of the future trend of historic places?",
    "answer": "This is somewhat difficult to answer, I guess, as the future is often unpredictable. Many people believe that historic places should be preserved because they depict a country's overall tradition and history. These places constitute an integral part of a nation's history, culture and heritage. On the other hand, others disagree with that. I think that some historic places would be retained either for usage, if possible, or for posterity in the future. However, the future is uncertain and depends, many times, on the decisions of political leaders and the powerful people. However, I believe that some significant historical places would become more important and would be preserved more carefully in the future. More tourists would be interested in visiting such places.\n\nTips: A good way to fully answer the question is to say something general about historic places and then justify your opinion. For example, you could say that you want them to be preserved or not. Give examples and predictions to put more articulation."
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "Question_id": 10,
    "question": "Will the government strengthen its protection toward historic places?",
    "answer": "I can't really know for sure, but I would say that these places must be protected no matter what. As mentioned, historic places reflect a country's history and culture and they are a nation's brand. To illustrate, Greek authorities make significant efforts to preserve and renovate the structure of the Acropolis and every year they perform programmes for the restoration of the Hill. They also work to make different monuments approachable by the tourists and also maintain their initial identity. So I believe, governments, all over the world, would be more careful to preserve and protect important historic sites."
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "Question_id": 10,
    "question": "What are the changes brought about by the historic place in the local economy and people?",
    "answer": "When I think of changes brought by the historic places, the first thing that comes to my mind is 'benefits'. Firstly, these places provide employment and income to many people, not only in some particular seasons with many tourists but also throughout the year. In addition, as these places are famous and a country is characterised by those, locals and foreign visitors will pay them a visit and this results in the popularity of the country. Furthermore, as a result of these visits, the whole economy will develop and these countries will flourish and prosper. People would learn about diverse cultural aspects and would be able to present their own cultures and custom to visitors."
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "Question_id": 10,
    "question": "What is the effect of tourists to such a place?",
    "answer": "Influx of tourists to these places might lead to both positive and negative consequences. Visitors would help create more jobs among the local people and help raise the budget to the government. Through the internet and social media, those tourists will share photos and videos of their activities and their friends will learn about those places. The visiting tourists bring many foreign cultures and customs which are often unknown to the local people. The growing tourists often increase the business opportunity in the local area.\n\nApart from the beneficial aspects, there are some negative implications as well. As these places are very crowded with a tremendous number of visitors, they become less tidy. It is not uncommon that foreign customs and culture brought by the tourists often threaten the local culture and the way of life."
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "Question_id": 11,
    "question": "What do you think are the important qualities for a news reporter?",
    "answer": "First and foremost, one of the essential characteristics of a news reporter is the dedication to his profession. Academic training would be another important aspect to become a great news reporter. Besides, being objective, curious, passionate to excel, motivated to do something better for people are some other important qualities a professional news reporter should have. Finally, being able to judge information received on different subjects and not misinterpreting facts are two other qualities every good news reporter should possess."
  },
  {
    "id": 36,
    "Question_id": 11,
    "question": "What's the main difference between a newspaper and a magazine?",
    "answer": "It's a really difficult question because as readers, people often think that these two are almost the same. But if we examine sincerely, we will notice that there are some differences between these two. First, newspapers contain short articles on current events and they are mostly daily and sometimes weekly publication. Magazines, on the other hand, include longer articles on a variety of subjects and are a weekly or monthly publication. Apart from these differences, there are some minor differences as well. For instance, magazines are smaller in size than newspapers and usually more expensive. Newspapers contain fresher contents than magazines. In addition, magazines are like a book while a newspaper is larger in size, though the number of pages is fewer than a magazine. So we could conclude that although these two forms of print media sometimes seem identical, there are many differences between them."
  },
  {
    "id": 37,
    "Question_id": 11,
    "question": "What's the function of a report to the society?",
    "answer": "A report contains useful information made with a specific intention in mind. With regards to the function of a report, we could say in brief that it is multifunctional. To begin with, it provides information on what has to be done or needs to be done. It points out aspects that deserve attention. Moreover, reports are used for keeping track of information and this action results in making decisions. Hence, they are used in different fields such as the government, business, education, science, and so on. People, who form the society, have the right to know and reports are often investigative to aware them of many issues of the society."
  },
  {
    "id": 38,
    "Question_id": 11,
    "question": "What kinds of books/newspapers/magazines do adolescents read in your country?",
    "answer": "Adolescence time is a transitional period of life so most of the children's hobbies and pastimes change during this time. As far as my country is concerned, I think that girls at adolescence read gossip and fashion magazines and novels with mainly romantic plots. For boys, they read sports magazines most of the time, but there are some of them who read novels as well. When I was a teenager, my peers used to read Harry Potter books and as far as I can remember they were mainstream.  \n\nTips: Adolescents in different countries read different kinds of books, newspapers or magazines. Just talk about the most popular types in your country. For example, you can say that boys read sports magazines, sci-fi, poetry, mystery, detective and adventure type books. With reference to girls, you can mention that they mostly read literature, romance, contemporary issues and beauty magazines."
  },
  {
    "id": 39,
    "Question_id": 11,
    "question": "With the popularity of the Internet, do you think newspapers and magazines will disappear?",
    "answer": "That's a controversial yet important issue to discuss. Some people believe that magazines and newspapers will continue to be publicized irrespective of the Internet's rapid progress. The way we are accustomed to reading a hard copy of a newspaper or a magazine will never be replaced fully. The appeal of reading something printed is in our blood and it would not fade away very soon.\n\nHowever, it is undeniable that a large number of people would read them on a computer or a handheld device. My personal belief is that as the Internet is constantly advancing, the publication of the press will be restricted to some extent and all the major newspaper and magazine companies will have their online versions for readers. I can see for myself that many people prefer reading the news online rather than buying newspapers, but that does not mean that they never buy a magazine or a newspaper or will not do so in the future."
  },
  {
    "id": 40,
    "Question_id": 12,
    "question": "What do you think is important for achieving happiness?",
    "answer": "I strongly believe that ordinary yet priceless things such as health, family solidarity and closeness, important people like friends who will always be there for you no matter what, and job satisfaction can definitely lead to happiness. I am opposed to the belief that money makes everyone happy and contented. Although money and wealth are essential elements for human life as they help people cover their expenses, do things they want and purchase materials people want, I don't think that they are the determinant factors. Furthermore, self-contentment could be another important ingredient for us to be happy. We can be happy with whatever little we have only if we have the self-satisfaction and self-contentment."
  },
  {
    "id": 41,
    "Question_id": 12,
    "question": "How do you celebrate some happy events?",
    "answer": "As I can remember when I was in my teenage, I used to hold parties at my home solely with my family and relatives to celebrate happy events. Especially on my birthdays, my mom cooked my favourite food and made my favourite birthday cake with chocolate. Now that I am not a teenager anymore, I go out with my friends, and in some special circumstances, with my family as well. For example, on my graduation day, I went to a Greek restaurant with my parents, brother and my five best friends and we had a really great time. Generally speaking, I would say that I am more of an introvert person, so I totally prefer to spend substantial time with few friends rather than having many people and typical big parties. My happy moments and celebrations are also related to my friends and family members."
  },
  {
    "id": 42,
    "Question_id": 12,
    "question": "What role do the camera and video recorder play in celebrating?",
    "answer": "I would say that these two tools, camera and video recorder, play an integral part in different types of celebrations. First of all, most people have moments of their childhood and memories from childhood are captured in cameras. To illustrate, some of the most important events such as birthday parties, weddings, graduations and so on are included in these jigs and in this way the moment is captured and saved for a long period of time. Furthermore, as some essential and happy events are recorded, they could be watched years later in order for some people to remember some significant events. A good illustration in my case is that on my 22nd birthday, my friends made me a really emotional video from all the years that we have been friends. Without the usage of the camera and video-recorder, this could never have happened."
  },
  {
    "id": 43,
    "Question_id": 13,
    "question": "Is there any difference between the traditional and modern education systems?",
    "answer": "I can't really know for sure because I have graduated from school many years ago, but I would try to answer this question from what I have heard and learnt about it. In the traditional system, teachers are present in a classroom and have an active role during the class because they do everything on their own. More precisely, verbal communication, interaction and the usage of blackboard are the main elements of this type of system. Books, pens, pencils, lectures, question-answer, written exam and grading are the main ingredients of the traditional education system.\n\nOn the contrary, in the modern education system, a teacher's role is restricted as technology does many things instead. With the use of computers and virtual classrooms, the method of teaching has changed to a great extent. Projectors, online classes, assignments, online learning system, online exams and assessments are the main ingredients of the modern education system.\n\nI believe that with both of these systems, students will be able to reap benefits as long as they are willing to study in collaboration with their teachers and academic activities."
  },
  {
    "id": 44,
    "Question_id": 13,
    "question": "What are the pros and cons of the current education system in your country?",
    "answer": "This is an important issue to talk about and I can't be accurate as I am not fully aware of the way schools function these days, but I will answer from my experience so far.\n\nA positive thing is that a combination of traditional and modern education methods are applied in our education system and this undoubtedly leads to better results. To illustrate, students are motivated to study and in this way, they develop their cognitive skills, acquire mental capabilities, assimilate the information provided more easily and they also build a well-rounded personality. Some other positive sides of our education system are that the syllabus is updated, the teachers and well trained, and the schools have a better learning environment these days.\n\nMoving to the downsides, some teachers don't deal with their students as much as it is required and this trend has a detrimental effect on children. Moreover, a better evaluation method is still needed to be implemented."
  },
  {
    "id": 45,
    "Question_id": 13,
    "question": "Do you think it is necessary to give comment or criticism to teachers?",
    "answer": "I strongly believe that criticising teachers isn't the appropriate course of action. The best and most effective method is giving comments and making plausible and constructive conversations about the issues that concern parents and students. Everyone should bears in mind that teaching is not as easy as many think it to be and parents should collaborate and interact with teachers and not assail teachers. Besides, it would be good to consider that from the moment someone chooses to become a teacher, he/she is willing to give his/her best."
  },
  {
    "id": 46,
    "Question_id": 13,
    "question": "How can a teacher make learning more interesting?",
    "answer": "It is really an interesting question that concerns most of the people, including teachers and parents.\n\nAllow me to say that teachers play the most important role in teaching and sharing knowledge among students. For example, when I was in secondary school, the most difficult subject for me was geography because of the overwhelming information about the different countries. My schoolmaster tried to make it more interesting by telling us different things about each country such as their culture, way of living, customs and famous people. In this way, he not only made the subject exciting but also managed to provide us with valuable information. Nowadays technology constitutes an essential part of everyday life, so teachers can take the opportunity to make things exciting and more interesting by connecting students to the documentaries that are relevant to the study. It is undoubtedly an effective way to stimulate students' interest and imagination.\n\nPersonally, I think that passion for teaching, a good relationship with students, telling stories that connect to the lessons and use of technology can make learning more interesting, engaging and effective."
  },
  {
    "id": 47,
    "Question_id": 13,
    "question": "Are there any subjects that shouldn’t be taught in school? Why?",
    "answer": "I don't think that this should happen. My personal belief is that everything that is taught in a school is useful and provides important information to students. Of course, there are different types of subjects and among them, some are more educational and useful than others, but I would say it's subjective and depends on a student's personal aims and objectives. For example, I wanted to be an economist since the secondary school and the requisite subjects for this were mathematics, business administration and physics. It was my personal preference but it didn't mean that history, literature and ancient Greek should be withdrawn. So, I don't agree with that and I support that all types of subjects should exist in a school curriculum."
  },
  {
    "id": 48,
    "Question_id": 13,
    "question": "How can the school help students overcome a problem with a certain subject?",
    "answer": "That's an important matter to discuss and it happens to almost everyone throughout their school years. However, there are some strategies that can be implemented to repress this kind of problem. Teacher's attitude is an essential element that helps children change their mindset about a specific subject and see it from a different perspective. Schoolmasters should urge their student to deal with this subject and make them understand it by modern methods rather than the conventional ones. Furthermore, they should encourage and not humiliate them in case children can't demystify the information provided. I believe if teachers and the school authority are sincere about helping students who have problems in specific subjects, this will be resolved with the help of reference books, consultancy and technology like the internet."
  },
  {
    "id": 49,
    "Question_id": 13,
    "question": "Do you think that visiting different websites has benefits for a student?",
    "answer": "Like any other technology, the Internet has both pros and cons for students. However, it is not the problem of the technology itself, rather the one who uses it. So, if students visit websites which are reliable, offers helpful information and study materials, they will definitely reap benefits from this. From different websites, students are able to read a wide variety of topics, but they should make sure that the websites they access are reliable and provide accurate information.\n\nOn the contrary, if a student visits websites that are not reliable, not suitable for their age, and offer only entertainment and no education-related materials, then it might be negative for them."
  },
  {
    "id": 50,
    "Question_id": 14,
    "question": "How often do you visit museums?",
    "answer": "Although I would love to go to museums more often, I have only visited three of them until now and that would make it three times that I have been to museums!\n\nAll of them were of archaeological type but I still remember the last one- in Greece. It was the Acropolis Museum and I went there at the age of 16, during a school programme for the restitution of the Parthenon Marbles which are located in the British Museum. It is a magnificent building and it reflects the greek civilisation with the inclusion of statues, monuments and even documentaries with the purpose of informing visitors not only from overseas but also from Greece about its exhibits. I strongly believe that it was the best educational experience of my life and I would induce people to pay it a visit when possible."
  },
  {
    "id": 51,
    "Question_id": 14,
    "question": "What type of museum is popular in your country?",
    "answer": "I come from Greece so I'm going to talk about the type of museums famous there. It is widely known that Greece has a really important culture and history, so there are numerous museums throughout the country. Archaeological and Folklore museums are the most common kinds and those are visited by the majority of people. Apart from these, biographical, ethnographic and historic museums are also really rife in our country. Furthermore, there are art museums and galleries and some other that are about industry, science and technology. To conclude, there are plenty of categories that satisfy everyone's preference and desire but Archaeological and folklore museums are most popular in our country."
  },
  {
    "id": 52,
    "Question_id": 14,
    "question": "What do you think of the importance of museums in history?",
    "answer": "My personal belief is that museums are of paramount importance and constitute an integral part of a country's history. As it is known, these constructions provide information about culture and heritage; in other words, museums keep history alive. To be more precise, museums include artefacts and different objects from the past and by placing them there, people are reassured that the items they see provide clear and accurate information about the history, rather than reading books and magazines in which most of the details are subjective and theoretical. In addition, if I'm allowed to speak in economic terms, I would say that museums are history's brands and trademarks."
  },
  {
    "id": 53,
    "Question_id": 14,
    "question": "How do you think of the heritage of a country?",
    "answer": "It seems to me that the heritage of a nation isn't determined by only one thing. To begin, monuments, sculptures and temples are essential and they are representative examples as far as heritage is concerned. For example, the Parthenon in Greece, Statue of Liberty in the USA, Hatshepsut's Mortuary Temple and Pyramids in Egypt, Tower of London in the UK are only some the most significant structures that reflect each country's legacy. History composes an important part as well, by informing people about the achievements and failures of a territory and the reason why something is known and studied by many. Lastly, museums which we were talking about earlier couldn't be missing from this list, not only for all the important aspects they have but also because they are connected with the beauty and grandeur of a country."
  },
  {
    "id": 54,
    "Question_id": 14,
    "question": "Compare museums nowadays and in the past.",
    "answer": "Anyone who pays a visit to museums could say that nowadays museums are more beautiful, modern, have a rich collection, and convenient to visit than in the past. To elucidate, in the past, only a few people had access to them but these days they are open spaces for public knowledge. Furthermore, much attention is given to the maintenance of the museums now than the past and most of the museums are renovated not only for their preservation but also to attract more public interest. In addition, technological advances have played a fundamental role; with videos and audios helping visitors understand what they see and that makes their experience more pleasant, informative and interactive than the past when these technological usages were absent."
  },
  {
    "id": 55,
    "Question_id": 14,
    "question": "Have you ever been to a foreign museum?",
    "answer": "The truth is I have never been to a museum outside my country, but I would really like to go someday. The first museum that comes to my mind is the British Museum in the UK and despite the fact that I have been living in England for the last three years, I never managed to visit this renowned institution. Some other museums that I definitely want to visit are the Metropolitan Museum of Art and National Portrait Gallery in the USA and the National Museum of Ireland."
  },
  {
    "id": 56,
    "Question_id": 14,
    "question": "What are the tourist attractions in your city?",
    "answer": "I live in Hatfield which is 30 km north of London and there are many things tourists can see and do there. Firstly, it is really worth seeing Hatfield House which is on the eastern side of the town. Secondly, Mill Green Museum and watermill, Hatfield Park Farm and Hatfield Public Library are places that someone should visit without a doubt. Finally, the University of Hertfordshire and The Galleria Outlet Shopping are some good and interesting structures for everyone."
  },
  {
    "id": 57,
    "Question_id": 15,
    "question": "Describe a war movie you like.",
    "answer": "I’m going to tell you about ‘Braveheart’, a war movie directed by Mel Gibson, who was also the leading character. The movie was released in 1995 and it was written by Randall Wallace. In the 14th century, William Wallace, a Scottish warrior, leads his people in a rebellion against the tyranny of the English King, who has given English nobility the 'Prima Nocta' - a right to take all new brides for the first night. The Scots were not pleased with the brutal English invaders, but they lack the leadership to fight back. Wallace creates a legend of himself, with his courageous defence of his people and attacks on the English. The film was nominated for ten Academy Awards at the 68th Academy Awards and won five: Best Picture, Best Director, Best Cinematography, Best Makeup, and Best Sound Editing.\n\nOther war movies you can say about: The Pianist, Saving Private Ryan, Black Hawk Down, Apocalypse Now, Good Morning Vietnam, War Horse, Downfall, Lincoln, and Imitation Game."
  },
  {
    "id": 58,
    "Question_id": 15,
    "question": "What’s the difference between the movies in your country and Hollywood movies?",
    "answer": "I believe that the movies in my country aren’t that good as Hollywood movies are. First of all, the budget is really low for local movies and that is why there are very limited opportunities. Not all scenes are impressive and there are no special effects, something that dominates in Hollywood. Furthermore, the actors in local movies aren’t so famous and talented, on the contrary in Hollywood they are of worldwide fame. There is a large variety of the topics and themes of Hollywood movies. However, our local movies do not deal with a wide range of themes. Finally, Hollywood movies are released and enjoyed worldwide while our local movies are mostly made for us except for some very few movies that get international attention."
  },
  {
    "id": 59,
    "Question_id": 15,
    "question": "What do you think of the violent films?",
    "answer": "I would say that it depends on the type of violence. To be more precise, I like movies with violent scenes because they’re interesting and include more actions. In those movies, the good wins over bad. It’s a kind of vindication and the message that good prevails over bad. I don’t like movies that involve rapes. In particular, I hate these movies. I would not say that it’s something that isn’t happening, but I think that promoting women’s humiliation and debasement is not a good thing. So, I would come to the conclusion that I partly like violent movies and specifically, it depends on the story. However, the unnecessary violence is not liked by all and I am no exception."
  },
  {
    "id": 60,
    "Question_id": 15,
    "question": "Why movies need computer techniques? Any example of movies using computer techniques?",
    "answer": "Well, computer techniques should be used to add some characteristics to movies so that they can be more impressive and believable. Especially nowadays this opportunity is much more in use than the past. Many things that were unfeasible are attainable now with computer technology in movie industries. A remarkable example could be ‘Avatar’, a movie that was critically acclaimed and had a million views worldwide. The groundbreaking visual effects used to make humans look like extraterrestrial beings were amazing and that was the primary reason that the film broke several box office records and became the highest-grossing film of all time in England, Canada and the USA."
  },
  {
    "id": 61,
    "Question_id": 15,
    "question": "Which parts of a movie are the most important and how to improve it?",
    "answer": "It is an undeniable fact that all the parts of a movie are extremely important, but it seems to me that more attention should be given to the finishing of a movie. There are many examples of movies that were very interesting but the end was extremely boring and disappointing. In this case, I totally believe that the end negates all the good things that happened in the rest of the movie and leaves a bad impression on the viewers. So, my opinion is that the last part/ finishing part of a film should be of paramount importance and it can be achieved by providing a distinct and not vague message to the viewers and making things clear in their mind.\n\nTip: You can say about other things such as the beginning, the plot, dialogues, directing, special effects or even the acting. It’s up to you and your personal opinion."
  },
  {
    "id": 62,
    "Question_id": 16,
    "question": "Say something about tourism development in your country, facility, services and the effect on the environment.",
    "answer": "In my country tourism industry plays a fundamental role not only in the summer, peak hour for tourism but also in other seasons. I was born and raised in Greece so I would say that tourism constitutes an indispensable part of my country's economy. To begin, because of the renowned Greek islands, thousands of foreign visitors come here on vacation every summer and this results in reaping benefits in all levels. More precisely, many facilities such as airports, hospitals, hotels and restaurants have been constructed and they aren't beneficial only to visitors but also to locals. Many seasonal stores operate this period and in this way, more people get employed and acquire an income, the whole economy is developed and consequently, the country prospers.\n\nApart from this beneficial part, though, there are some detrimental repercussions on the environment, due to the tremendous number of guests. Most people, dispose of their rubbish wherever they want and because of this, roads and pavements become really unsightly, smelly and unhygienic and this equals to damage to a place's landscape. In addition, during the constant usage of means of transport and especially planes, the CO2 emissions can cause air pollution which is harmful to the environment and public health, as it can cause respiratory diseases.\n\nTip: If your country is a tourist destination you can mention the things that are written above or anything else you desire. If this isn't the case, you can just say that your place isn't preferred by visitors and justify your answer in order to give a complete answer."
  },
  {
    "id": 63,
    "Question_id": 16,
    "question": "What is the importance of the travel and tourism industry?",
    "answer": "It is widely accepted that tourism is an essential sector of a country’s economy and in this way, numerous benefits can be gained. The most important contribution of travel and tourism could be argued that is in the economic sector. As mentioned previously, tourism provides employment and earning sources for many people. It also brings many facilities as well, not only to visitors but also to local inhabitants. By the constructions of hotels, travel agencies, airlines, restaurants and other leisure industries, which are used by the visitors, a great amount of money is earned, and thus a country's GDP develops.\n\nMoreover, except for the direct results, there are some other indirect benefits that play a really important role in a nation's economic development. Given the fact that people can meet each other in person, international business relationships and profits like competitive advantage, economies of scale, higher exports and innovation could be derived. Lastly, the investment can be encouraged as trade and investment are interdependent."
  },
  {
    "id": 64,
    "Question_id": 16,
    "question": "What do you think the function of tourist guides?",
    "answer": "A tour guide is a person who guides the visitors to explore different tourist attractions, explain the historical aspects of a place or a thing in the language of their choice. Guides help travellers to understand the culture of the region and the way of life its inhabitants and therefore, it is imperative that they are knowledgeable about the cities and countries where they work. Hence, they provide information on a country's culture, history, customs and heritage and they try to do their best in order for foreign visitors to understand what they see in-depth. Although it's relatively easy to become a tour guide in many parts of the world, in southern Europe it's more difficult due to strict laws and it is regarded to be a unique profession with great prestige."
  },
  {
    "id": 65,
    "Question_id": 17,
    "question": "What are the differences between a serious party and a friendly party?",
    "answer": "I think that there are many differences between these two kinds of party. In the former, the attire is often more elegant with guests wearing costumes and ties, while in the latter, this doesn't always happen and people wear more casual clothes, such as jeans, t-shirts and so on. In addition, serious parties are often more of a professional type, whilst with friendly parties, this isn't always the case. For example, a serious party includes a party with a person's colleagues, employer and boss and in case of a friendly party, some peers, fellow students or relatives enjoy the party. Moreover, it could be argued that serious parties are mostly held in restaurants or bars and most of the time are expensive, while friendly parties are held at our houses or cafeterias and are cost-saving."
  },
  {
    "id": 66,
    "Question_id": 17,
    "question": "Why are some people late for parties intentionally?",
    "answer": "This is a really interesting question and to be honest, I have never thought about it. I can't find a logical explanation of why someone will do something like that and I would describe it as an immature and unscrupulous action. But, unfortunately, there are many, who belong to this category and some of them are friends of mine as well. A reason that comes to my mind is that someone doesn't want to go to a party but they are forced to do so. Indeed, there are many occasions and especially related to workplace or parties thrown by relatives where people are sometimes forced to be present. In this case, the only solution is going many hours after the commencement of the party. This is the only reason I can think of and partly justify this action.\n\nTips: If you are one of them who intentionally go to a party late, just say the reason you do so and give the best possible explanation you can think of to convince the examiner that your action is justifiable."
  },
  {
    "id": 67,
    "Question_id": 17,
    "question": "Why do some people like the party while others hate it?",
    "answer": "I don't really know for sure, but I would say that it's a matter of individual character and preference. Some people are introvert and like to keep a low profile who don't like places and events which are crowded. Furthermore, if parties are held in houses, the mess is unavoidable and oftentimes the damages are irreparable, so for the host, it could be said that is a traumatic experience.\n\nMoving to those who love parties, it could be argued that it's a way in which people come together and have fun. It's arguably true that due to the excessive working hours and the busy lifestyle, people have drifted apart and become alienated. Parties are great opportunities for reunions and substantial conversations. A further reason which is a little ludicrous is because of the tasteful and delectable food. I can say about some of my friends that - the first thing that comes to their mind when they hear that they are invited to parties is 'food' and they are instantly inundated with positive feelings."
  },
  {
    "id": 68,
    "Question_id": 17,
    "question": "What would you do if the guests you have invited to a party feel bored?",
    "answer": "The first thing I would do if my guests are bored at a party that I have hosted is to turn on the music or change my playlist. Some people don't like conventional and rife types of music and prefer something else. If music couldn't help, I would ask them what they want to do to have fun and adjust to their desires and preferences, if possible. Furthermore, if nothing of the above could produce a positive result and change their mood, I would play a game to attract their interest or tell some stories from our different experiences and stages of life, which would definitely lead to some laughter and joy. I would finally arrange some indoor games and would declare some prizes for the winners to warm up the guests.\n\nTips: Some other options to cheer up the bored guests in a party could be- changing food and drinks, sugar and coffee sometimes make someone recharged, introducing each other so that they can talk, giving them space and autonomy is useful as well because they are free to do whatever they want without restrictions."
  },
  {
    "id": 69,
    "Question_id": 17,
    "question": "Will there be more and more people to attend parties?",
    "answer": "Yes I think so. I truly believe that the number of party lovers will increase in the future. The opportunities to gather together with friends and relatives are shrinking in modern days and people would not want to miss parties where they can meet people, relatives and enjoy their time. Parties would be a way of relaxing and taking breaks for many busy employees and the increasing number of party attendees these days gives hints that in the future it will increase further."
  },
  {
    "id": 70,
    "Question_id": 17,
    "question": "Why do some people like to host parties at a restaurant or hotel rather than home?",
    "answer": "For some, arranging a party at home takes too much effort and time. Decorating the home, cooking different food items and then worrying whether the guests would like the taste, as well as cleaning the house, and doing the dishes are difficult. Giving the location of the venue to guests is not easy either. Moreover, in our modern outset, inviting many guests at a small apartment is not feasible. So, it's only natural that many people these days prefer to hire a party centre at a hotel or a community centre to throw a party."
  },
  {
    "id": 71,
    "Question_id": 18,
    "question": "How has education changed in your country in the last 10 years?",
    "answer": "The truth is that ten years ago the educational system wasn't the same as it is now and many aspects have changes in our education system. In the past, teachers used to engage conventional methods of education to teach their students and the only means they utilised was blackboards and textbooks.\n\nFurthermore, as far as I'm concerned, schoolmasters paid more attention to their student's weaknesses, problems and needs and the bonds between them were stronger than it is today. Moving to the present, the existing ties between teachers and children have become more impersonal and unfortunately, many teachers willingly keep a distance from students in the classroom. In addition, technological advances play a vital role in teaching and the methods used in the classrooms these days.\n\nTo conclude, I prefer the past educational system (as it was 10 years ago or so) than it is now. Education and teaching aren't only about the internet and technology. The internet does not make someone literate, but a strong bond between a teacher and a student does."
  },
  {
    "id": 72,
    "Question_id": 18,
    "question": "What changes do you foresee in the next 50 years?",
    "answer": "It seems to me that in the forthcoming future, the changes will be tremendous. First of all, it won't be necessary for teachers to be present in the classroom as everything is going to be accomplished by the use of technology. For example, students will become knowledgeable about different matters from the comfort of their home and they will correspond with their tutors online rather than having personal relationships. Of course, it still happens these days to a certain extent, but in the next 50 years, I believe that this will be the way of teaching exclusively.\n\nGoing further, I think that apart from some basic subjects such as literature and mathematics, other subjects will be optional and each child will have the opportunity to choose the subject they want to take even in primary schools. From my point of view, I cannot say for sure if this is the appropriate course of action, but one thing is clear, continuous education and learning will be accepted and embraced by all."
  },
  {
    "id": 73,
    "Question_id": 18,
    "question": "How do the expectations of today’s school leavers compare with those of the previous generation?",
    "answer": "In the past school graduates just hoped to find a job in order to earn a salary and cover their living expenses. Some of them did not even look for a job but continued their family business. They didn't have as high expectations as school leavers have these days.\n\nIn many cases, nowadays school-leavers don't have realistic expectation and they wish to have a higher position with a great remuneration, even without professional experience. Furthermore, these days knowledge isn't the only thing required for a good job as skills, experience, discipline and adaptability, to name but a few, are prerequisites in order for someone to enter the labour market. That, however, was not the case in the past"
  },
  {
    "id": 74,
    "Question_id": 18,
    "question": "What role do you think extracurricular activities play in education?",
    "answer": "It is commonly believed that extracurricular activities play an important role in education and have many benefits both in personal and professional life. I quite agree with that as such activities enhance our capability and improve our way of thinking. First of all, children with extracurricular activities learn how to collaborate and co-exist with other peers and learn about soft skills. In addition, a great opportunity is provided to them to interrelate with others and develop and evolve their interpersonal skills. Hence, these types of activities can create a feeling of contribution, as children are involved in different things and this will lead them to boost their self-esteem. Lastly, all these advantages will help children build a well-rounded personality and an exceptional character and will benefit the school and teachers by having well-mannered and conscious students."
  },
  {
    "id": 75,
    "Question_id": 19,
    "question": "Is friendship important in your culture? How many close friends can you have?",
    "answer": "Friendship is really important and I think that it should be of paramount importance in all cultures worldwide. Our friends are our siblings and they are the people we chose to have in our lives. Moreover, a friend is a person you can call whenever you are sad, happy, angry, excited and so on. We should take into account that many people in different countries consider their pals to be more valuable than their family. As far as I’m concerned, I believe that someone can have two or three close friends.\n\nTip: This is just a personal opinion about the number of friends someone can have. It's up to you and your experience."
  },
  {
    "id": 76,
    "Question_id": 19,
    "question": "Are friends more important than family?",
    "answer": "That’s a really difficult question to answer. It is widely accepted that parents are the people with whom we are connected by blood and they are also our closest relatives. Friends, on the other hand, are just some people we come across during our lifespan and it’s our choice whether we will keep them in our life or not. But, as I mentioned earlier, there are some who consider that friendship is more important than family and the reasons for this may differ. From my point of view, I would argue that parents and friends should be equally important in someone’s life because a fulfilling and complete life consists of both family and sidekicks. I believe life without parents is like a tree in the desert and life without a friend is death without a witness.\n\nTips: You can say that \"family and friends are equally important in someone's life\", or \"the family is more important than friends\" and even \"friends are more important\". In either case, cite arguments and examples and state your personal opinion."
  },
  {
    "id": 77,
    "Question_id": 19,
    "question": "What are the important things among good friends?",
    "answer": "First and foremost, people should take into account that friendship is a sacred notion in someone’s life and a two-way street as well. Friends should invest in real feelings and there are some virtues that are crucial. For example, true friends must be honest with each other, compassionate, be there when needed, affectionate, tender and supportive to mention but a few. Every friendship has its ups and downs but when emotions are real any hindrance can be eliminated. To conclude, a wise and useful phrase that comes to my mind is “a friend in need is a friend indeed”."
  },
  {
    "id": 78,
    "Question_id": 19,
    "question": "Do you have any friends from a foreign country?",
    "answer": "Unfortunately, I don’t, but I really hope to make new acquaintances and meet people from overseas. In this way, I am convinced that I’ll become more broad-minded and tolerant.\n\n Actually I do. I live and study in England; so I have met many people from different countries even from different continents. I really like consorting with them because we can swap opinions, make helpful and substantial conversations and learn new things about culture, custom and religion. In addition, we can travel to each other’s country and accomplish dreams and desires that otherwise might be unachievable. Last but not least, we can immerse ourselves in a new language and gain more knowledge."
  },
  {
    "id": 79,
    "Question_id": 19,
    "question": "What are the differences between real-life friends and pen friends?",
    "answer": "The difference is significant because in the first case, there are stronger bonds. For pen friends, the existing ties are loose. The former, are the people whom we see in the flesh and blood, share our sad and happy moments, spend time with, have frequent contacts and share some intrinsic moments. The latter, are people that correspond with each other and it could be considered as a kind of distant relationship. Furthermore, a real friend is able to be with you whenever you need him/her, while for a pen friend this is not feasible."
  },
  {
    "id": 80,
    "Question_id": 20,
    "question": "Which one is better - being introvert or extrovert?",
    "answer": "I think there is no definitive answer to this question as it is a moot issue and all of us have our personal opinions about it!\n\nAn introvert enjoys solitude and operates as a loner most of the time. Furthermore, he/she has only a few friends and doesn't open up easily to others about personal matters. Great scientists, poets, artists and talented people were often introverts. Being an introvert means people will have more time to think and create something new. On the other hand, being extrovert means that someone is friendly, outgoing, sociable, affectionate and has large groups of friends. Oftentimes, they engage in different kinds of activities and they share things that concern them with their friends.\n\nRegarding which type of personality is more preferable, I would say that 'ambivert people' is the answer to me. I don't think that being totally introvert or extrovert is good, but combining these two types would be the most appropriate, at least this is what I believe."
  },
  {
    "id": 81,
    "Question_id": 20,
    "question": "What type of person are you?",
    "answer": "That's a really difficult question for me and I confess that I haven't even thought about it before! The truth is that I have only 5 close friends, they are like siblings to me and I discuss anything that happens in my life with them. I wouldn't say that I'm always an outgoing and sociable person except for the times when I really want to. For example, I am not the type of person who will go out every day and meet new people but when I was at university, I showed others the social part of myself in order to make friends. I know it sounds a little weird and creepy, but this is the way I am. So, I would say that I'm more of an introvert person, with some elements of extroversion when needed.\n\nTip: Say about your type of personality, for example, whether you are introvert or extrovert and justify it with examples from your life. You can also say that you are an ambivert person by having characteristics from both types - introvert and extrovert. In any case, exemplify your answer."
  },
  {
    "id": 82,
    "Question_id": 20,
    "question": "What important aspects do you consider to make new friends?",
    "answer": "'Friend' is a sacred notion to me and they are as important as family. First of all, as I mentioned earlier, friends are nothing less than siblings to me and they are the people we have chosen to have in our life for whatever reason. A real and strong friendship should be based on true feelings and not on selfishness. Virtues like love, trust, honesty, compassion, affection and kindness are indispensable parts of this concept. Moreover, being there when your friend needs you, help them whenever you can, console them when they get hurt and be happy with their achievements are some of the main characteristics. Everyone should invest in emotions and show them to friends in certain circumstances. Besides, if people don't give and receive love in their life, nothing would have a meaning and I believe friends are there to do just that."
  },
  {
    "id": 83,
    "Question_id": 21,
    "question": "Why childhood is important for us?",
    "answer": "It is an indisputable fact that childhood is the best period in our life. Children are carefree, play all the time and have no concerns. In addition, childish memories are really important and many times determine children's life and personality. It's true that there are many cases when people with an extremely unpleasant childhood tend to be mentally disturbed not only when they reach adulthood but also later in their life. So I would jump to the conclusion that it's imperative that a child is raised in a caring, loving and supportive environment in order to maximise their future well-being and become emotionally- secure adults."
  },
  {
    "id": 84,
    "Question_id": 21,
    "question": "What changes have you gone through from your childhood?",
    "answer": "It's obvious that all of us have undergone changes through the transition from childhood to adulthood. First of all, external appearance has completely changed, as my body has developed and I have grown taller. In addition, I would say that I am able to maintain my composure when difficulties come up and I am more mature than the time when I was little. Furthermore, I am tolerant of diversity and I have learnt to respect other people's preferences, opinions and attitudes. Lastly, my educational level isn't the same as it was in my early years, as I have graduated from university and specialised in a particular field."
  },
  {
    "id": 85,
    "Question_id": 21,
    "question": "What are the differences between childhood friends and college friends?",
    "answer": "That's a really interesting and substantial question. Friends during childhood are just some children who we spent time with and share some common interests. They are more like our playmates than soulmates. On the contrary, college friends are some important people with whom we share a really strong bonding and become close to. Furthermore, most of the time friends from higher educational institutions are like siblings and long-time relationships are built, as they are based on true feeling such as trust, compassion, love and so on. For example, my best friend from university is like a brother to me and also my best man and in this way, we have sealed our relationship while I do not have any childhood friends whom I still communicate"
  },
  {
    "id": 86,
    "Question_id": 21,
    "question": "What do you think makes someone a good friend to a whole family?",
    "answer": "It seems to me that the main element in order for someone to be considered a friend to all members of a family is having common values and interests. If these two characteristics are absent or not compatible, it's really difficult for someone to be accepted as a family friend or to hang out with.\n\nMoreover, if parents see that someone has a good personality and some basic virtues that support the notion of friendship, it is likely that they will like and accept this person to their family.  In my opinion, family friends play an important role as there are many cases when parents consort with some people they consider friends, and many times it is likely that their kids also interact with those people."
  },
  {
    "id": 87,
    "Question_id": 21,
    "question": "Do you think we meet different kinds of friends at different stages of our lives? In what ways are these types of friend different?",
    "answer": "I totally agree with that statement as I believe we have different expectations and requirements for our friends in different stages of our life. When children are in primary schools, they just have one or two friends and this is because at that stage they are not capable of assessing and appreciate the importance of friendship. In the early stages of our life, we require friends who would love to play with us, do things that we like to do. So, these relationships are slack and nothing is invested as far as feelings are concerned. However, we start understanding the significance of this bond in high school as we make some friends who have similar interests and can help us in studies. Friends during puberty, on the other hand, are in many cases the most important in someone's life and often these relationships are really strong and based on a solid foundation. At that period of life, people's' relationships are true and substantial as real feelings such as love, affection, support and trust are dominant. When we start our career, we will have many friends who are basically colleagues. In the old age, people usually have friends who are more like family members.\n\nSo, I would say that friends in the very early ages are just some playmates who kids hang out and spend some time with and the teen to adult stages include very important and worthy people that are much more than friends."
  },
  {
    "id": 88,
    "Question_id": 21,
    "question": "How easy is it to make friends with people from a different age group?",
    "answer": "It's a controversial issue as some would say it is quite easy to make friends from different age groups while others would deny it.\n\nIn my opinion, the most important characteristics of making friends are communication and common views. In this way, people are able to talk about different things, make meaningful conversations and swap ideas. If these elements don't exist, even among the people of the same age group, then it's really difficult for someone to make friends. I would say that usually, people find it easier to have friends of same age groups, but if effective communication and common views work smoothly between two persons of different age groups, they can become good friends. For example, a friend of mine who is around my age has a close friend of 60. When I found about that I was surprised, but when I saw that they have so much in common and they have great times together, I totally endorsed it. As far as I'm concerned, I don't have friends who are much older than I am but I have younger friends and common interests make us a really tight group."
  },
  {
    "id": 89,
    "Question_id": 21,
    "question": "Do you think it is possible to be friends with someone if you never meet them in person?",
    "answer": "It’s an interesting question to answer and I would say that it is possible indeed, but it's not the same as having friends who we meet personally and interact face-to-face. Nowadays, especially due to technological advances, more and more people chat and interact with each other via chatting, calling and social media applications and in this way, they develop different kinds of relationships. There are many cases when someone talks with another person on a constant basis and share personal things, experiences and they turn out to call each other 'friend'. But in my opinion, I would say that this person is more of an e-buddy rather than a real friend. A friend is someone that people can see in the flesh and consort with them regularly."
  },
  {
    "id": 90,
    "Question_id": 21,
    "question": "Is this a real friendship?",
    "answer": "As I extensively mentioned earlier, this isn't true friendship, at least in my taste. Many positive sentiments may be created, such as rapport, confidence and happiness, but friendship is much more than only a word and it entails that people have a contact on a regular basis and hang out with each other. E-friendship is a different type of friendship, I would say an impersonal one because friends aren't able to meet each other in person and the only thing they can do is talk by typing keystrokes on the keyboard or make video calls. Such friendship is growing faster due to our reliance on technology, but they are not real friendship, in my opinion."
  },
  {
    "id": 91,
    "Question_id": 21,
    "question": "What kind of influence can friends have on our lives?",
    "answer": "It is argued that friends are the second most influential persons in someone's life, after the parents. A famous saying ‘A person is known by the company he keeps’ is indeed a reflection that we are greatly influenced by the friends we have. Especially at adolescence, children are impressionable as they form their personality and character and oftentimes they copy their peers. During this time good friends can instil positive attributes and elements in a person while the opposite is also true.\n\nFriends constitute a big part of our life and they play a very important role.  They can contribute to the creation of positive feelings for us such as happiness, self-confidence, esteem and control and can also delude us to have negative feelings and activities. Hence, they can be determinants of someone's character as friendship can play a vital role in a person's beliefs."
  },
  {
    "id": 92,
    "Question_id": 21,
    "question": "How important would you say it is to have friends from different cultures?",
    "answer": "In my opinion, having friends from diverse cultures is extremely important and helpful. Initially, people learn many things about other cultures such as history, customs, values and points, and this way their knowledge is enhanced. Furthermore, it promotes diversity and cultivates tolerance and understanding as well as positive changes in our attitude. For example, by having a friend from a completely different culture, people can swap opinions, broaden their horizons and become tolerant about things they have not faced before. To conclude, I reckon that it is essential that people have pals from different countries because as far as I'm concerned, this could only lead to positive outcomes."
  },
  {
    "id": 93,
    "Question_id": 26,
    "question": "How parents' decisions affect their children's life?",
    "answer": "Our decisions determine our actions and the future paths of our life. Wrong decisions can often ruin lives while prudent decisions often lead to prosperity and happiness. I would say that parents should be extremely careful when they are about to make a decision for their children and take into account their children's future as well.\n\nTo be more precise, there are many cases that parents want to move to another city or even to another country for whatever reasons they have and due to this decision, children become unhappy and face difficulties. I vividly remember a friend of mine when I was in high school, that she had just moved to Greece and the difficulties she experienced were frightful. She didn't even know how to speak Greek and apart from the fact that she experienced racism, she was devastated as she had lost all of her friends and her dreams. Another point to consider is parents' desires about their children's future career. Unfortunately, parents' intervention in youngsters' studies is a frequent occurrence and many times they do wrong choices. To illustrate, many parents force their kids to study a subject that they want and dream about, with the excuse that it was their own wish but they weren't able to accomplish it.\n\nFurthermore, they urge their children to enrol at a university depending on career prospects, being indifferent to kid's real dreams and aspirations. Because of these, children will end up trapped in disenchantment, misery and manipulation. On the other hand, the parents' wise decision will affect the children's life very positively."
  },
  {
    "id": 94,
    "Question_id": 26,
    "question": "What important things do you consider while making a big decision?",
    "answer": "That's an interesting question. The decisions that I take mostly depend on the existing and potential circumstances. In my case, when I decided to leave Greece and move to England, there were endless matters that concerned me. First of all, the financial opportunity was the predominant and most significant one. If I didn't have any money I wouldn't be able to travel and start a new life here. Furthermore, career prospect was the second issue that plagued me during this decision. Due to the financial crisis that has agitated Greece and a big part of European countries, wages have declined and income has collapsed, so it's almost impossible to get any form of employment. Therefore, I decided to take matters into my own hands and go and set my dreams in motion. Moreover, the overriding factor to this resolution was that my brother was in England too and I would have a really loving person of mine who always was by my side and supported me.\n\nSo I consider the present situation, related variables of the action I am going to take, future prospect, possible outcome (both positive and negative) while making any major decision.  \n\nTip: I preferred to answer this question with a recent example of my life. You can do the same as well by talking about a job, studies, marriage, cohabitation, moving to another country and so on. For example, for the job, studies and moving somewhere else, you can say that you take into consideration things like job opportunities, salary, satisfactory working conditions, friends and relatives, husband and wife, type of facilities available, difficulty in adjustment and so on."
  },
  {
    "id": 95,
    "Question_id": 27,
    "question": "What type of music is famous in your country?",
    "answer": "In my country almost all types of music are popular. I would say that although pop is a little more renowned, it doesn't mean that other kinds of music like rock, jazz and metal aren't rife as well. International music constitutes a big part of people's entertainment, especially at bars and night clubs. In addition, in Greece which is the country I was born, traditional music plays a really essential role as at the majority of music events, the country music has the predominant role and makes everyone's time exciting and hilarious.\n\nTip: Each country has different types of music. For example, you can say that in your country traditional or international music is well-known and dominant rather than conventional kinds, such as pop, rock and so on."
  },
  {
    "id": 96,
    "Question_id": 27,
    "question": "What are the influences of western music in teenagers in your country?",
    "answer": "The truth is that western music isn't that popular among the teenagers in my country and only a few people, especially grown-up tend to prefer western music. I think this is happening because that kind of music is a form of American folk music which was created by those who inhabited in the Western United States and Canada and celebrated the life of cowboys there. Because of its special and unique characteristics, it isn't enjoyed by many in Greece and this could be justified by the fact that its popularity has declined in the last 40 years in my country. As far as teenagers are concerned in my country, most of them are not influenced by it.\n\nTip: The answer given is totally subjective and concerns my country of birth. If you come from or live in a country that western music is really popular just mention it and try to give some details. It is really pleasant when someone learns something useful that they were not aware of before in a conversation."
  },
  {
    "id": 97,
    "Question_id": 27,
    "question": "Why is music important?",
    "answer": "Music is the food and vitamins for our soul. It can heal our wounds, remind us of our good time, help forget our misery, inspire us and represent our cultural identity to the world. I strongly support the idea that music is indispensable in people's lives and it produces extremely beneficial implications.\n\nMusic can touch our heart and mind and some melody can arouse different emotions in us. Whenever people are in love, face a crisis, make or break a relationship there are songs that can describe the whole situation and motivate people. Hence, music helps people interpret and understand things from different perspectives and heals any existing mental wounds. In addition, via music, people can relax and have their mood elevated after busy days of a massive amount of duties and obligations. Last but not least, music encourages and promotes tolerance as it can connect people regardless of their country, culture and religion."
  },
  {
    "id": 98,
    "Question_id": 27,
    "question": "Which one is more important: traditional music or western music?",
    "answer": "This is quite difficult to exactly answer this because I don't listen to either type. But I would try and say that both of them are equally important, at last in some countries. The former, traditional music, describes and depicts every country's tradition, customs and views in life and is the brand ambassador for each country. The latter, international music, concerns a very particular type and location. Traditional music may have different forms depending on the country or even a city, while western music is something more fixed as it deals with the western lifestyle, appeal and stories. So, I would infer that the answer to this question is subjective and has to do with people's origins, nationality and preference, but there is no case that I would say that any of them is more significant than the other.\n\nTip: It is my personal opinion but it does not mean that this is the only way to answer this question. You can choose one of the types above and clarify your preference. For example, for traditional music, you can say that it is pretty important as it describes local cultures and is unique in each place. Western music refers to a completely specific kind and has a singular background."
  },
  {
    "id": 99,
    "Question_id": 32,
    "question": "What do you think about 'Photography' as a career?",
    "answer": "This question is equally interesting and difficult for me. My personal belief is that ‘Photography’ is a great occupation, not only because it is indispensable for many different fields but also because through it people can discover the world. To be more precise, by taking a photograph, the moment is frozen and the depiction is saved no matter what. Photographs decorate books, magazines, paintings and many other things. So, it's an essential vocation that is associated with other jobs, similar to it or not. In addition to this, photographers travel a lot across the world and see new places, landscapes, buildings and so on. It is something that apart from a profession is also a hobby and provides entertainment and spiritual education to photographers. As I see in my country the career of a good photographer is quite bright and full of possibility. With online journalism, this has become an even more demanding profession."
  },
  {
    "id": 100,
    "Question_id": 32,
    "question": "What makes a good photograph?",
    "answer": "Although I love taking pictures for a long time, I haven't been concerned with the details and technical aspects of photography thoroughly. But I would say that the most important part of a good photograph is the theme of the picture. For example, a beautiful landscape could make a photo really impressive by just having beautiful colours or scenery. Furthermore, the angle that the photograph is taken from is significant as well because, with the technique, a simple theme can become an attractive one. Furthermore, lighting, focus on proper objects and use of the right camera can make an ordinary scene to become a beautiful photograph."
  },
  {
    "id": 101,
    "Question_id": 32,
    "question": "What are the improvements the latest technologies has brought in photography?",
    "answer": "Technology has contributed to tremendous improvements in photography and its storage and distribution. First of all, smartphones and iPhone have built-in high-resolution cameras and that has made taking pictures easier and more convenient. People these days are no longer obligated to carry a professional camera with them to take pictures. Pictures taken from a mobile phone can be transferred and viewed on a personal computer and can be stored online.  The photo editing software can not only change some basic characteristics of the photo taken but also the whole picture and can make it more appealing. With the help of technology and software, an ordinary picture can be converted into a professional one without significant efforts. Technology has offered us advanced cameras with more power and features and those cameras can take pictures in an extreme environment like in the water. I would say that camera, photography and presentation of photos with the help of technology has got a higher dimension."
  },
  {
    "id": 102,
    "Question_id": 32,
    "question": "How often do you take photographs?",
    "answer": "The truth is I used to take pictures very rarely in the past, but after I created my Instagram account, I've become accustomed to taking pictures very frequently. I really like capturing every important moment and other significant events with my friends and family and sharing them with my online friends has become a common activity for me. That doesn't mean, of course, that I take pictures all the time but I try not to miss capturing worthy moments and sceneries. My Instagram account, which is photograph storage and photo-sharing website, has led and inspired me to use my camera more frequently than ever before."
  },
  {
    "id": 103,
    "Question_id": 62,
    "question": "Describe the seasons in your country.",
    "answer": "I come from Greece so I'm going to tell you about the seasons there. There are four seasons in Greece- Autumn, Winter, Spring and Summer and each one lasts three months. September, October and November constitute the autumn season, with basic characteristics the transition from hot to cool and mild weather. Winter starts in December and ends in February and the main features of this season are rain, cold weather and sometimes snowfall. Christmas and New Year are celebrated during the winter season and despite these adverse and unwanted weather conditions, there are many people who declare that this is their favourite period of the year. Spring and summer are the last two seasons of the year. Spring consists of March, April and May and the latter June, July and August fall in the summer season. In spring flowers and trees blossom and the temperature fluctuates between 15 and 25 degrees. Summer is identified by hot weather, many insects and of course the sun, sea and vacation."
  },
  {
    "id": 104,
    "Question_id": 62,
    "question": "What is the most comfortable season in your country?",
    "answer": "This question is kind of ambiguous for me and the answer, I believe, would differ from person to person. From my point of view, although I adore summer, I can't stand the overwhelming hot weather and mosquitoes, which I'm allergic to. Spring is also a lovely season, but during this season I suffer from blooming flowers and I am forced to take medication to dampen this harsh and unpleasant situation, causing many side effects. Winter is a favourite season of mine because Christmas and New Year are involved, but I can't stand the constant rainy and extremely cold weather. So, I would jump to the conclusion that autumn is the most comfortable season for me, because the weather is great, neither too cold nor too hot, there aren't many blooming flowers and mosquitoes and other types of insects. I believe many others in Greece would also agree that this is the most comfortable season.  \n\nTip: Pay attention that the question is about the most comfortable season and not your favourite one. So you have to tell the examiner about the season that is convenient in your own country. The answer may vary because each country has different types of seasons with regards to weather conditions and climate"
  },
  {
    "id": 105,
    "Question_id": 62,
    "question": "What's the necessity of clothes in a particular season?",
    "answer": "It is commonly accepted that suitable clothes are worn to protect people from different weather conditions and to ensure comfort in various seasons. More precisely, in the winter people wear attires in order to remain warm and the most representative examples are sweaters, boots, coats, scarves, gloves and so on. In autumn and spring, people don't wear too heavy clothing because the weather is milder in comparison to winter. The summer is characterised by the hot and sunny weather in most places and people prefer to wear clothes such as shorts, t-shirts, sleeveless garments, sandals and caps. So I would infer that in each of the four seasons people need different types of clothes in order to be able to stand the various weather conditions without any problems."
  },
  {
    "id": 106,
    "Question_id": 62,
    "question": "What are the seasons you have in your country but other countries do not.",
    "answer": "That's a difficult question actually and requires knowledge about seasons in other countries too. The truth is I'm not knowledgeable about other countries' seasons, but I would try and answer that question using the information I have known so far. I think that in Africa seasons are much different than those of other countries. Africa has all the four seasons mentioned, but not in the same months. Summer, the so-called 'Calving Season', is considered to be from December to March and although is called 'summer', the highest temperature is 28C and the lowest 15C. Autumn, 'Green Season', starts in late March and ends in June. Winter, 'Jump Season', is from July through to August and despite it's called 'winter', most days people only need a t-shirt by lunchtime. Lastly, spring is the 'Dry season' and lasts three months, September, October and November. Interestingly some Asian countries like Bangladesh have six seasons. The summer season in Arabic countries are quite hot and their seasons are quite different than that of many European countries."
  },
  {
    "id": 107,
    "Question_id": 88,
    "question": "Do you enjoy giving and receiving gifts? Why or why not?",
    "answer": "I really love it! I enjoy quite a lot of exchanging gifts. To me, this is a token of appreciation and a symbol of care.  \n\nI like a lot to have presents from people I appreciate, care and love. I think that by gestures like gift exchange, you are able to judge who is a real friend or how valuable you are to someone. For example, as gifts are given in special circumstances, it helps you understand if someone likes you, appreciates you, loves you or value you. It not only depends on the kind of gifts and prices but also how carefully and honestly the gifts were selected and given to you. In addition, this gesture is pleasant as it means that somebody shares a significant moment of their life with you.\n\nGiving presents to someone is quite enjoyable because through this you can show your respects, love and care for someone. Gifts often reflect someone’s personality and character and also visualise how much you care for someone. For me, giving gifts to a relative, family member or friend is quite fascinating and an act of showing I care.  \n\nTips: It is very less likely that someone would not like to give and receive gifts. However, if you are one of them, who doesn't like receiving presents, you can just say the reasons. Some examples are that- you feel that you are obligated to repay them, you might not like the present but you must keep it because the opposite is disrespectful, you just invite someone to an important event of yours not for bringing gifts but because you want them there for you.\n\nAbout those who don't like giving presents you can say that it is costly, you don't know someone so well so you can't pick a present for them, gifts do not always represent that the giver cares about you or it is a custom that is inflicted by other generations, people often give flowers, toys and chocolate and you are allergic to flower, do not like chocolate and hate toys."
  },
  {
    "id": 108,
    "Question_id": 88,
    "question": "Who usually gives you gifts?",
    "answer": "My parents, relatives and friends mostly give me gifts. But, I received some fabulous presents from my godmother when I graduated from university. However, I will never forget the gift my brother gave me and it was a ticket to England!\n\nTip: You can say that you receive presents from parents, friends, grandparents, godmother and godfather, uncles, cousins, siblings even teachers, colleagues and bosses. If you want you can mention one or two examples when you were given some important gifts."
  },
  {
    "id": 109,
    "Question_id": 88,
    "question": "Who do you give gifts to?",
    "answer": "I mostly buy presents for my friends on their birthdays. This is the most common case, but I also give presents to my parents on their wedding anniversary. So I would say family and friends are the people I buy gifts for. The latest gift that I gave to one of my friends on her birthday was a book he wanted to have."
  },
  {
    "id": 110,
    "Question_id": 88,
    "question": "In your country, when do people usually give gifts?",
    "answer": "I don't think that in my country this custom is very different from that of other countries. Specifically, people buy presents on name days and birthdays, wedding anniversaries and graduation ceremony. There are also some cases, such as when someone is admitted to a university or is promoted at work, but these aren't so common in my country. Some festivals also encourage people to exchange gifts.\n\nTip: If in your country this isn't the case, you can just mention in which occasions people give presents. Remember that these answers are based on my experiences and personal opinions and it doesn't mean that they represent every case in every country."
  },
  {
    "id": 111,
    "Question_id": 88,
    "question": "What kinds of gifts do they give?",
    "answer": "The type of presents depends on the occasion, a person's personality, choice, economic & social status and so on. You can't give the same present all the time because not everything suits everyone and this is completely reasonable. Some examples that I can think are clothes, books, perfumes, shoes, household appliances, and bags, especially on birthdays. But, there are some cases that presents are much more different and expensive. When someone, for example, gets married you can give them household and electric appliances, money or even a car."
  },
  {
    "id": 112,
    "Question_id": 88,
    "question": "Do you think gift-giving customs are different now than they were in the past? How?",
    "answer": "I am not quite sure how the gift exchanging was in the past generation but I believe that they don't differ much. I assume that in the past, presents were given on the same occasions as we do nowadays. The only thing I reckon that's different today is the kind of gifts given. The reason and occasions of gift-giving remained the same throughout the generations, I guess."
  },
  {
    "id": 113,
    "Question_id": 88,
    "question": "Do you think they will change in the future? How?",
    "answer": "It's a thoughtful issue but my personal opinion is that it may change in the future. In future people will be able to buy presents not only on usual occasions but also whenever they want to. Furthermore, if some commodities become more affordable there is a possibility that this trend will be much different in the future than it is now. People will be more practical while choosing a gift for others and the range of gifts would increase. However, the grand gesture and underlying reason for gift-giving will remain almost the same as it is today"
  },
  {
    "id": 114,
    "Question_id": 95,
    "question": "What kind of things give status to people in your country?",
    "answer": "Well, the innocent-sounding word \"status\" is, in fact, hard to define and it varies from person to person. Generally speaking, a large house in a posh area, a corporate job with higher remuneration, luxurious cars, well-decorated house, higher education and a foreign degree, fame and expensive electronic gadgets are some common symbols of status in our country. To some people, material gains are more important than morality to have social status while very few people consider otherwise."
  },
  {
    "id": 115,
    "Question_id": 95,
    "question": "Have things changed since your parents’ time?",
    "answer": "I think it has not changed significantly and earthly possessions and money were determining factors for having social status during my parent's time as well. However, they also considered someone's character and morality for social status than we do today."
  },
  {
    "id": 116,
    "Question_id": 95,
    "question": "Are people in modern time more focused on their career than the past?",
    "answer": "Yes, people these days are more concerned and focused on their career development than ever before. Increasing population and competition, our declination towards material gains and loosely family ties have fueled this. In the past, someone used to put his family and morality well above his career. However, this is often not the case in today's world. It is not entirely our's fault. Without being career conscious it would be hard for any of us to sustain in the modern workplace."
  },
  {
    "id": 117,
    "Question_id": 95,
    "question": "Do you think advertising influences what people buy?",
    "answer": "I think advertisements have a great magnetism on us as consumers. We are surrounded by advertisements and consciously and unconsciously these adverts influence our choices to buy a product. For instance, if a customer is given four perfumes of different brands and is asked to buy one, he would go for the brand he has heard about or seen on an advert. We want to buy something we have heard about and this is where the advertisers tap into. We even end up buying things that we do not need only because advertisements lure us to do so!"
  },
  {
    "id": 118,
    "Question_id": 95,
    "question": "What makes us buy things we do not need? Why is so?",
    "answer": "We live in a materialistic world where we have plenty of options. The emergence of the throwaway society has further fueled our habit of buying more than we actually need. We are never happy and with the frequent release of new and improved electronics and household items, we are tempted to buy things we could do without just fine."
  },
  {
    "id": 119,
    "Question_id": 95,
    "question": "Should advertisers be allowed to track our online activities?",
    "answer": "This is an interesting question to deal with. As a consumer and a regular user of the internet, I believe our privacy is at stake and advertisers should not be allowed to track our every online activity to leverage their advert campaigns. However, from the advertisers perspective, they find it quite natural to track our activities to offer us the most suitable products or services which will fit our demands. They believe it maintains the advertisement ecosystem. However, we should be wary of this tracking mechanism and avoid being targetted by following the safe-browsing policies. There should definitely be a boundary to restrict advertisers and brands to get our private data."
  },
  {
    "id": 120,
    "Question_id": 115,
    "question": "How can technology make our life easier?",
    "answer": "Technology can impact our lives in many ways and so far technological advancement has made our life easier than ever. First of all, the internet has contributed to this to a large extent. This invention has dominated our daily life and made it easier by providing a massive amount of information on different subjects.  It has also made communication faster and easier. For example, you can just press a button and all the desired results can be retrieved instantly. When I was at university, I found many helpful resources on the internet, while in the past students had to go to libraries and spend endless hours of searching. Going further, communication and shopping have improved as well. Nowadays, people across the world communicate whenever they want, whilst some decades ago this entailed time and money. Online purchases are a constant phenomenon, as you can buy anything you want by a few mouse clicks and of course at a better price. Finally, the smartphone is a representative example of technology that is used by everyone and because of its multiple functions things that were unattainable in the past, have become completely feasible now.\n\nTechnology has made it possible to cure diseases that were incurable in the past. It has improved the way we travel, cook, play, make a relationship, spend our leisure time and so on and on. Space exploration has enhanced our perspective of life and the universe while we can better fight natural disasters with the help of technology. In fact, we are blessed with the advancement of technology in every step of our life."
  },
  {
    "id": 121,
    "Question_id": 115,
    "question": "What are some greatest inventions you know about?",
    "answer": "There are many remarkable inventions that have changed our lives and humankind. The Automobile and light bulb are two of the most important things that were invented by Karl Benz and Thomas Edison in 1885 and 1870 respectively. The first device helps people commute whenever they want and wherever they are and the second has made working in dark places and at night feasible. We can't do without computers and the internet as well. The former was invented by Alan Turing, a British Mathematician and is a machine that takes information in, is able to manipulate it in some way, and outputs new information. The latter, allows people to access almost any information located anywhere in the world at any time. Its effects on business, communication, economy, entertainment and even politics are profound. Among other greatest inventions, I should probably mention the wheel, printing press, paper, Penicillin, Integrated Circuit and camera.\n\nTip: These are only some of the inventions I consider that should be mentioned. There are plenty of other devices that can be included. Some of the greatest inventions of human history are given below from which you can select your personal favourite to speak about:"
  },
  {
    "id": 122,
    "Question_id": 115,
    "question": "Why should we restrict the use of the mobile phone in public places?",
    "answer": "The primary reason is that sometimes they can be intrusive and irritating. For instance, when they are used in hospitals or in public libraries they are really disturbing. Mobile usage in public libraries disturbs people from concentrating so they must always be turned to silent. A further reason is that cell phones can be considered as an antisocial means. In a little more detail, most of the time people send messages and make calls to their friends and relatives and this deprives them of face to face communication. A final reason could be health issues that are caused by cell phones. Due to radiation emission, headaches and migraines are a frequent occurrence as well as other health-related problems such as cancer, multiple sclerosis and heart problems."
  },
  {
    "id": 123,
    "Question_id": 115,
    "question": "Why mobile phones are gaining its popularity?",
    "answer": "It's an undeniable fact that mobile phones are very useful. For example, in case of an emergency, you can make a call and avert something unpleasant, something that without mobile phone possession would be unattainable. Moreover, these appliances enhance communication and help people retain relationships that they might otherwise be lost, take pictures to keep memories, access the internet and include different types of applications as well. So, all these functions are combined and contained in a single device, otherwise having different appliances for every single function would be very expensive and space-consuming. This is less expensive to purchase and have many handy applications and usages. These are the main reasons cell phone are gaining its popularity so rapidly."
  },
  {
    "id": 124,
    "Question_id": 115,
    "question": "Can you do without your mobile phone?",
    "answer": "Unfortunately, the answer is no. Due to the fact that it's multifunctional, it constitutes an integral part of my life. I use it constantly every day to make calls and talk with my friends and family, send messages, access the internet, take pictures. I think I'll have a very difficult time even if I lose it for a while."
  },
  {
    "id": 125,
    "Question_id": 172,
    "question": "What type of qualities you prefer to make friends?",
    "answer": "The two most important qualities that I always prefer are positive mentality and honesty among friends. If someone has these two qualities, I will become his/her friend easily. Apart from that, I look the way he or she makes a conversation, criticise others and behave with others. Finally, I would also look for common interest as I believe having common interests and similar views make the friendship stronger."
  },
  {
    "id": 126,
    "Question_id": 172,
    "question": "Do you have many friends? How much time do you spend with friends?",
    "answer": "I used to have quite a large number of friends during my college years. Nowadays I have comparatively fewer friends, but they are very close to me. I have around 3-4 close friends and many other good friends whom I really like to discuss, talk and spend time with.\n\nAs I have got busy these days, I spend around 5-6 hours with my friends weekly. Sometimes, it varies from 3 to 10 hours on an average."
  },
  {
    "id": 127,
    "Question_id": 172,
    "question": "What is more important to you- your family or your friends?",
    "answer": "I would say family comes first. However, I would not say that my friends are not important to me. My family is my first identity and I love all of my family members a lot. They, especially my parents, have done a lot for me. They are, in fact, still sacrificing for the betterment of my life. This is unparallel and could not be expected from anyone else.\n\nOn the contrary, friends are important to enjoy our time with them, help each other, enjoy gossip, debate, visit places and share things that we would often hesitate to share with others and good friends are like a great comfort and support in life."
  },
  {
    "id": 128,
    "Question_id": 172,
    "question": "Why we admire some people while we do not like others?",
    "answer": "I think there is no specific laws and rules for admiring or disliking someone. From my experience, I can say that we admire someone who we find helpful, amiable and talented. People who are selfless and works for the greater goods are often admired. For instance, I have neither met Thomas Alva Edison nor Mother Teresa. But I admire both of them for the things they have done for humanity. Then we often revere our parents due to their great sacrifices for us and this admiration comes naturally. Sometimes we are helped by people who we never expect us to help and they become admirable to us. For example, I was once helped by a total stranger on a serious danger and I still remember him and think him with high admiration.\n\nOn the contrary, disliking comes mostly from someone's behaviours, acts and way of life. For example, if someone behaves rudely, we immediately dislike him. I guess we have a natural way of reacting depending on someone's attitude towards us. We can also dislike a corrupted person and a person who is quite selfish and harmful to others. I would say the opposite reasons for liking someone make us dislike someone in most of the cases."
  },
  {
    "id": 129,
    "Question_id": 197,
    "question": "How to make a good first impression (informal situation)?",
    "answer": "Today I will talk about how to make a good first impression. I will talk about why it is important, and what you can do to help create a good impression when you meet someone for the first time.\n\nThere is a saying ‘you only get one chance to make a first impression’! This is true and that is why it is important to make a good first impression. If you make a bad first impression it can be difficult to change in future. When you meet someone for the first time they will form an opinion of you based on how you look, how you behave and what you say. Lots of people are nervous when meeting other people for the first time. If you remember this it will help you to be more confident. Body language is very important. If you smile and look friendly, then most people will smile and be friendly in return. However, in some countries body language can be a bit different. For example, in some cultures you should look someone directly in the eye to be polite, in other cultures, it is rude to make direct eye contact and could be disrespectful. Try to notice how the other person is reacting to you. For example, if they look uncomfortable perhaps you are standing too close, or if they look confused, perhaps they do not understand what you are saying!\n\nIf you are meeting someone for the first time in an informal or social situation, then the most important thing is to smile. Think about how you could introduce yourself. You might say your name and what you do, and then ask the other person something about themselves. This can be a great way to start a conversation, people will appreciate it if you are interested in them too. Usually, in informal situations people do not shake hands, they may just nod and say ‘hello’, but if you are not sure what to do, follow the lead of the other person. If they offer out a hand then they are expecting you to shake it. Sometimes people will move forward to hug you at a party even if you have not met them before, then it is OK to hug them back!\n\nIf you think about when you have met someone new, try to remember what impression they made on you and why. If they smiled a lot, were friendly and enthusiastic you probably liked them straight away. Try to create that positive first impression with everyone new that you meet and you will find you make lots of new friends and widen your network easily!"
  },
  {
    "id": 130,
    "Question_id": 227,
    "question": "What would life be like without music?",
    "answer": "Life without music would be quiet and dull. What would we do at parties besides eating and talking? That might as well be a meeting. Think about the best party you’ve ever been to, how vibrant and outgoing everyone was. Especially when everyone’s favourite jam came on. Music helps me focus on projects when the house is soundless. In the past, I would drive around town aimlessly at night with nothing but music and my thoughts. This helped my creativity tremendously."
  },
  {
    "id": 131,
    "Question_id": 227,
    "question": "Which is more important to you, music or TV?",
    "answer": "Although television takes up a big chunk of my life I could probably do without it. Music, on the other hand, is irreplaceable. I’m thinking to myself I could read the news & also read a novel that the blockbuster movie was adapted from. Consequentially, I cannot read a song. Novels are famously known for being better than the movie. There is no possible way to hear music in any other form. It all boils down to what can be replaced and what can’t."
  },
  {
    "id": 132,
    "Question_id": 227,
    "question": "What kind of music do you like?",
    "answer": "I’ve always had an infatuation with music since I was a kid. My family likes to remind me of the time when I was two & I learned to say “Jackson! Jackson!” then hobble/hop around when his songs were played. Although my taste for music has evolved & diversified since then, music still holds a special place in my heart. I listen to all types of music & I am open to new music. Having said that, as I am writing this I am listening to classical music because it helps me concentrate and be more resourceful. The most common type of genre I listen to is Hip-Hop or Rap. I really feel that rappers recite more contemporary poetry.  There are a few R&B artists I listen to regularly."
  },
  {
    "id": 133,
    "Question_id": 227,
    "question": "What musical genre do you really hate? Why?",
    "answer": "I detest American Country music. It has got to be the lamest and depressing music genre available to the public. I cannot pinpoint the exact reason why I abhor this heinous excuse for music but I will try. Country music is extremely patriotic, quite irritating. America is number one when most of the people that listen to that type of music probably have never left the proximity of their area code. Music CEO’s realise that the white American population are losing jobs to “foreigners” so country music artists use that and say white America should love a pure America. It’s a clever way to be racist. When in truth no one is a True American. The lyrics are too simple but try too hard to be meaningful. Country music has a kind twang that I loathe. It will never grow on me & I try my hardest not to judge the people who listen to country music."
  },
  {
    "id": 134,
    "Question_id": 227,
    "question": "What do you think of music your parents listen to?",
    "answer": "My father has the same affection, if not more, for music as me. While I was growing up I have fond memories with the family & there was always traditional or classical Iranian music playing during these moments. Although I don’t have any Iranian music on my computer & never choose to listen to Iranian music I do like some of it. However, I am not crazy about some of today’s popular Iranian songs because they always seem to be furrowing their brows while griping about love."
  },
  {
    "id": 135,
    "Question_id": 227,
    "question": "Why do humans like music so much?",
    "answer": "Without looking up scientific facts why the human species is drawn to music I can muse that music has been a part of humans since the existence of man. Cavemen created drums and hopped around to the beat while circling a fire. Music evokes a feeling in people & I think that at its core that is why humans appreciate music so much."
  },
  {
    "id": 136,
    "Question_id": 227,
    "question": "Why is music important to you?",
    "answer": "Music plays an important role in my life. Whatever emotion I am feeling or mood I am in, I pair it with music. Some people listen to Adele when they are sad or Pitbull when they are happy. Music is the soundtrack of my life. Certain songs come on and it teleports me back to a moment while I was listening to that same song, usually a happier time too."
  },
  {
    "id": 137,
    "Question_id": 227,
    "question": "What influence do you think music has on life?",
    "answer": "Music doesn’t influence me like it used to. When I was 12 I started listening to hip-hop and it slightly influenced the way I dressed and somewhat how I acted. Case in point, when I saw Dr Dre wearing a black fitted baseball hat, I always wore one. Now I am older and music doesn’t have that type of influence on me but some music does affect my behaviour or mood. If I am listening up-tempo music it usually goes well with a party or my good music, whereas slower tempo music helps me relax and unwind."
  },
  {
    "id": 138,
    "Question_id": 227,
    "question": "What is the best time and place to listen to music?",
    "answer": "That’s the beauty of music; you can almost always listen to music. I feel the best time to have music is in social gatherings like when you are with close friends and you create a soundtrack for that occasion. At the same time, a meeting where you are trying to work is not an appropriate time to listen to any kind of music; even white noise."
  },
  {
    "id": 139,
    "Question_id": 299,
    "question": "Some people think that education should be about memorising the important ideas of the past. Do you agree or disagree? Why?",
    "answer": "I disagree with the view that education should about memorizing the important ideas of the past mainly because that would essentially undermine the whole purpose of education. In fact, education (proper education that is) is like a “ray of light” with which we can see, learn and understand the things around us so that we can pick and choose what’s good for us and what’s bad for us for in the present time as well as in future. Besides, everything doesn’t repeat in the same way at present time or future time as it did in the past, and therefore memorizing important ideas of the past won’t do any good when the situation is different. Finally, innovation and creativity of a person are far more important than the amount of information he or she can memorise, and from this perspective, we should focus on creating a generation who are creative and can bring innovative solutions to problems rather than memorise past ideas only."
  },
  {
    "id": 140,
    "Question_id": 299,
    "question": "Should education encourage students to develop and share their own ideas?",
    "answer": "Yes, I do think that education should encourage students to develop and share own ideas because this practice would encourage them to be “creative” and confident in their own abilities. Besides, sharing ideas among each other would inspire them also respect each other’s opinion in a way that would collectively benefit our entire society. Finally, this kind of practice would also allow the students to understand the “bigger picture” (understanding what things are happening and “why” in the greater scheme of thing) by looking past their differences and their damaging effects."
  },
  {
    "id": 141,
    "Question_id": 299,
    "question": "How do you think teachers could help students to develop and share their own ideas?",
    "answer": "In order to help students to develop and share their own ideas, teachers should first let them know that they (students) also have many great ideas and that those ideas are also important. Besides, teachers could also arrange for some kinds of “incentives” or “rewards” (like offering “extra credits” for the ideas) in order to encourage their students. Finally, teacher themselves can actually have some “real debates” with their students on burning issues that are affecting their society so that the students feel more “engaged” in real-time."
  },
  {
    "id": 142,
    "Question_id": 299,
    "question": "Should employers encourage their workers to have new ideas about improving the company? Why?",
    "answer": "Yes, I do think that employers should encourage their workers to have new ideas about improving the company mainly because, after all, it’s the workers who keep the company running at the end of the day. Besides, when the workers are allowed to have new ideas and implement them accordingly, they feel more “empowered” and “responsible” in order to deliver the best results. On top of that, this practice creates a rather congenial atmosphere at work where workers and employers co-operate even more among each other."
  },
  {
    "id": 143,
    "Question_id": 299,
    "question": "Do you think people sometimes dislike ideas just because they are new? Why?",
    "answer": "No, I don’t think that people sometimes dislike ideas just because they are new as, in fact, there are many other factors besides that. But probably the main factor is that people are not given ‘enough’ time to get themselves immersed in the new ideas and learn about their pros and cons. Another factor is that they are not offered “enough compensation” most of the times for their extra time and efforts, which they used, to eventually learn about the new ideas and implement them."
  },
  {
    "id": 144,
    "Question_id": 299,
    "question": "What is more difficult: having new ideas or putting them into practice? Which is more important for a successful company?",
    "answer": "In my humble opinion, none of the things, which involve “having new ideas” and “putting them into practice\" is so easy. Both are important and could be difficult in times for ordinary companies.\n\nBut they could be implemented if the work environment encourages and nurture the creativity and dedication of the employees. A successful company always very carefully nurture the culture of having new ideas and putting them into practice without putting any extra burden on its resources, such as “human resources” and ‘assets’. Besides, a successful company is also dynamic enough to adjust and adapt almost regularly and, as such, the issue of having new ideas and putting them into practice becomes easier. However, it can be difficult for some ordinary companies."
  },
  {
    "id": 145,
    "Question_id": 356,
    "question": "What are some famous tourist spots in your country?",
    "answer": "Although for the last three years I have been living in England, I am originally from Greece and I'm going to tell you about some renowned tourist places in Greece. The most well-known and famous tourist destination in Greece is the Acropolis. It's an area in Athens, the capital city of Greece, with lots of cafeterias, restaurants, souvenir stores and of course. On the top of the hill, there is the Parthenon, the most important surviving building of Greece. Apart from Athens, Greek islands are a choice for many foreign visitors. Mykonos, Crete, Skiathos and Santorini are some of the most popular places among the visiting tourists with thousands of tourists every year, especially in summer. Greek food, sunlight and sea in combination with Greek hospitality make these spots some of the most crowded and desirable places for the visitors all over the world."
  },
  {
    "id": 146,
    "Question_id": 356,
    "question": "What are the positive impacts of tourism in your country?",
    "answer": "First of all, tourism is an essential sector of a country's economy. As far as my country is concerned, tourism provides employment for many people and those earning members contribute towards the development of our country. Furthermore, as visitors spend money on different things and activities, the whole economy is developed and it leads to increasing prosperity. Furthermore, different types of facilities that are mainly constructed for visitors, such as airports, hotels and hospitals, are also beneficial to the locals. Finally, tourism in Greece helps our own traditions and customs to be well-known among the people of other nations. I would say tourism in my country is quite important."
  },
  {
    "id": 147,
    "Question_id": 356,
    "question": "What are the negative impacts of tourism in your country?",
    "answer": "Apart from the positive outcomes that my country accrues from tourism, there are some unwanted situations and negative impacts of tourism that cannot be denied. Due to a huge number of tourists, the costs get higher each year and this is a serious problem for local people. The increase in prices is considered a serious problem and as a result locals having difficulty meeting their basic daily needs.Going further, dispose of rubbish is another undesirable result because people often throw their garbage wherever they want and the places there become smelly and unhygienic. Moreover, foreign cultures are constantly being exposed to our countrymen and this is a serious threat for our unique traditions and customs. In Greece, a common problem of tourism is that excessive drinking habit in such places makes people lose themselves and do unethical and petty things"
  },
  {
    "id": 148,
    "Question_id": 356,
    "question": "What do you think are the reasons people visit new places?",
    "answer": "This is an interesting and plausible question. From my point of view, the primary reason why someone visits a new place is to learn about its culture and history. Culture is shaped by a country's history and in this way people are able to learn more about other customs, points of view, values and overall civilisation. This helps people to broaden their horizons and also leads them to become more open-minded, accept other's opinion and also encourages tolerance and understanding. Furthermore, it cultivates positive changes in attitude and promotes diversity. A further reason for visiting other countries and new places is the holiday. As people want to relax and recharge their stamina, they combine their vacation with travelling and meeting new places and people. Finally, visiting new places is kind of refreshing and attractive. This relieved us from our stress and gives us a fresh start in many cases."
  },
  {
    "id": 149,
    "Question_id": 356,
    "question": "What can you tell about the future of tourism industry in your country?",
    "answer": "This question is both difficult and uncertain. In the present, the tourism sector in Greece seems to be an influential and profitable, but as things are becoming worse due to the recent financial crisis, it's really debatable and the situation is constantly deteriorating. As mentioned, especially after the financial crisis that plagues the whole country, income has collapsed and wages have declined and unfortunately, it's becoming even worse as time goes by. But, as Greece is a history itself, people are optimistic and they hope that this sector won't face any problems and will continue to attract visitors from all over the world."
  },
  {
    "id": 150,
    "Question_id": 380,
    "question": "Why do we like receiving gifts?",
    "answer": "Well, receiving gifts help to uplift our mood. It also makes us feel special in most of the cases. Besides, receiving gifts also show how we are cared by the others. Overall, this is a joyous event for us. For all the reasons, we like to get presents."
  },
  {
    "id": 151,
    "Question_id": 380,
    "question": "Can we sometimes hate a gift?",
    "answer": "Uhhh… This is a critical question to answer. In most of the cases, people do not mind receiving gifts unless they are given by someone they really abhor or if the gift is intended for personal benefits. But there might be some occasions or particular types of gifts which may make the receiver feel sorry or may swell up a sense of discomfort or if they remind any unpleasant event, people may not prefer to have a gift."
  },
  {
    "id": 152,
    "Question_id": 380,
    "question": "Do you enjoy giving and receiving gifts? Why or why not?",
    "answer": "Yes, I do enjoy both receiving and giving gifts. When I receive gifts, I feel happy. It points that the people who send gifts to me are those who actually care for me. And they also provide me with the best things that I can use in my everyday life. So, I am happy with the gifts. And when I send gifts, I try to consider some of the specific issues and try to get the presents which would be preferable to the receivers. Being able to give something offers us a kind of pleasure that is incomparable."
  },
  {
    "id": 153,
    "Question_id": 380,
    "question": "Who usually gives you gifts?",
    "answer": "Usually, I receive gifts from my parents, siblings and obviously from my friends. Besides, when there are any social occasions and I invite my relatives, they also bring some sort of gifts for me. And I love those. I probably have got the highest number of gifts from my father."
  },
  {
    "id": 154,
    "Question_id": 380,
    "question": "Who do you give gifts to?",
    "answer": "Well, I usually give gifts to my parents, teachers, relatives, my friends, and my college mates. When I am invited to any event, I give gifts to the host. I have given the highest number of gifts to my parents and most of them were handmade items."
  },
  {
    "id": 155,
    "Question_id": 380,
    "question": "In your country when do people usually give gifts?",
    "answer": "People usually give gifts marking occasions like birthday, anniversary, graduation day and obviously they exchange gifts on the Christmas day. Apart from that, when someone invites others to visit his house, people usually buy some presents for the host and their children."
  },
  {
    "id": 156,
    "Question_id": 380,
    "question": "What kinds of gifts do they give?",
    "answer": "They exchange gifts which could be used in the daily life. Sometimes, they give gifts which look nice on the showcases. Toys, dresses, perfumes, chocolates, electronic devices, flowers, books and household appliances are the most common gift items in our country."
  },
  {
    "id": 157,
    "Question_id": 380,
    "question": "Do you think gift-giving customs are different now than they were in the past? How?",
    "answer": "Yes, the gift-giving customs have changed. Earlier, people used to visit shops to get the right type of gifts for their receivers. But now they rely on the e-commerce websites to get their gifts. Besides, in the past, people used to give some physical gifts and now they are moving for e-gifts like sending an e-card for someone's birthday instead of sending some chocolates. Moreover, book as a gift item has lost its appeal and electronic gadgets have emerged as most common gift items these days."
  },
  {
    "id": 158,
    "Question_id": 380,
    "question": "Do you think they will change in the future? How?",
    "answer": "Uhhh… well, the things will change in future too. The emergence of the e-shops has made it easier for people to get or send the gifts on their doorsteps. People will start relying more and more on technology to send gifts on different occasions. Hence, the appeal of receiving or exchanging gifts might have a great fall."
  },
  {
    "id": 159,
    "Question_id": 469,
    "question": "What types of weather do people in your country dislike most? Why is that?",
    "answer": "In England, it rains all the time and it's really cold here on such days. I think that most people hate when it's raining and windy at the same time because apart from the fact that they can't see anything and want to move forward, the pressure of the wind makes them go backwards. Something else that really gets me on my nerves is that my clothes get wet and I can't use my umbrella because of the wind.  \n\nTip: You can also say that you don't like hot weather or even the snow. Just think of the weather in your country and mention which is the worst one for you."
  },
  {
    "id": 160,
    "Question_id": 469,
    "question": "What jobs can be affected by different weather conditions? Why?",
    "answer": "It seems to me that different weather conditions can affect different occupations. Builders and farmers are negatively affected if it rains heavily.  For example, if the weather is rainy, people who work outside cannot work properly. Pilots and ice-cream sellers are two other professions that are affected by bad weather as well. In the first case, rain, snow and wind have a great impact on schedules while for the ice-cream sellers, the volume of sales and the whole business depends on the season and weather."
  },
  {
    "id": 161,
    "Question_id": 469,
    "question": "Are there any important festivals in your country that celebrate a season or type of weather?",
    "answer": "I cannot recall such festivals or celebrations in my country. However, I am certain in many countries this is quite a common trend to celebrate different weathers and seasons. For instance, the first day of the year, Rainy season, Autumn and Spring are often celebrated in India and Bangladesh. If we look back in our history, our ancestors mostly celebrated different festivals which were based on different seasons and weathers.       \n\nTip: Think of different kinds of festivals in your own country and mention a few of them and how they are celebrated.  \n\nIf there is no such festival in your country, simply state that these types of festivals are not celebrated in your country. Just remember, if the answer is negative, don't be upset that you said very few words. As mentioned, not all of your answers can be extended."
  },
  {
    "id": 162,
    "Question_id": 469,
    "question": "How important do you think it is for everyone to check what the next day’s weather will be? Why?",
    "answer": "It's very necessary to know the weather forecast because people should know the type of clothes they should put on. For example, if it's going to rain, they'll wear boots, jacket and of course take an umbrella with them. In addition, it's important for the means of transport they are going to use, for instance, if they want to go to work by car, bus or on foot. Finally, if they have any kind of plans they should be informed about the weather conditions because their plans can be ruined by bad weather. So I would say people's activity, dress and type of vehicles they will take depends on weather condition and that is why they should always check the next day's weather. From my experience I can say that people do not do that, often suffer and regret a lot."
  },
  {
    "id": 163,
    "Question_id": 469,
    "question": "What is the best way to get accurate information about the weather?",
    "answer": "I would say that watching the weather forecast on TV or the internet is the best ways to be informed about the weather conditions. But, we should be very careful because the internet can provide inaccurate information so we must be sure that the site we have access is reliable. Apart from that cross-checking different TV channels and websites is another good idea to get more accurate weather forecasting."
  },
  {
    "id": 164,
    "Question_id": 469,
    "question": "How easy or difficult is it to predict the weather in your country? Why is that?",
    "answer": "It's really difficult to predict accurate weather condition in my country because the weather in England fluctuates a lot. For example, a few days ago when I woke up at 9 am, the sun was shining and ten minutes later it started raining heavily. Two hours later the wind was blowing and for the rest of the day, the weather was like that. The only thing that is standard is the low temperature in the winter. The weather forecast thus often quite tough and unpredictable in England.  \n\nTip: Talk about the weather condition and percentages of the accurate weather forecast in your country. In many countries, this is really predictable. For example, in Greece the winter is cold and the summer is really hot. In some other countries, it's totally unpredictable. Just analyse it as much as you can and speak accordingly."
  },
  {
    "id": 165,
    "Question_id": 470,
    "question": "What are the most popular kinds of TV programmes in your country? Why is this?",
    "answer": "Although I don't watch TV very often, I think that TV series stands in the first place among popular TV programmes. There are different types of TV series such as soap opera, drama, romance, adventure, science fiction, crime and investment, comedy and so on. For example, Sherlock Holmes is a very popular TV series not only in England but also in other countries. Regarding the reasons why this is happening, I would say that those TV series are very interesting, entertaining and you can spend your free time watching it.  For instance, when I watched a police procedural television series, I learnt almost everything about crimes and investigations and that turned out to be even educative. These types of TV series has a great variety of topics and the plots are very attractive. That is why people do not want to miss any episode of their favourite TV series.  \nTip: Every country has its own popular TV programmes. This is just an example and it's based on my personal opinion. So don't take for granted that this is the only correct answer. You can talk about news, talk show, investigative programmes, debate show, talent hunt show, reality show, sports programmes etc as the most popular TV programme type in your country."
  },
  {
    "id": 166,
    "Question_id": 470,
    "question": "Do you think there are too many game shows on TV nowadays? Why?",
    "answer": "As I said earlier, I am not a TV fan! However, whenever I surf TV channels I can obviously feel the number of overwhelming sports channels. This is proof that people nowadays watch more sports channels and sports telecasting than ever before. Likewise, the number of game and quiz shows on different TV channels is also quite high. I have noticed my mom watch two game-shows and she likes them very much. People often watch game shows because those programmes are entertaining and educational at the same time. The competitive nature and challenges attract many viewers to watch such programmes.  Sometimes there are questions for the viewers and as a viewer, someone often gets the chance to earn prizes or the opportunity to participate in the live show. These are in my opinion are the reason games shows are more popular these days and there are so many of them.      \n\nTip: Your answer could be negative as well. Not every country has many game shows. If so, you should say the reasons you believe this is happening. Also, give one or two personal reason(s) why game shows in your country are not popular."
  },
  {
    "id": 167,
    "Question_id": 470,
    "question": "Do you think TV is the main way for people to get the news in your country? What other ways are there?",
    "answer": "Well, I come from Greece, so I would say yes, TV is the main source to get news in Greece. In my country, TV is the main way for most of the people to get information about different news and events.  Only a few young people and adults get the news via the internet and the elderly from radio and newspapers too.  \n\nIn England, where I currently live in, TV is a popular means of getting information but I wouldn't say that it's the most popular source for news and information. People of all ages rely on the Internet, social media and newspapers to get news."
  },
  {
    "id": 168,
    "Question_id": 470,
    "question": "What types of products are advertised most often on TV?",
    "answer": "Actually, this is a difficult question because I think that most of us don't pay much attention to TV's advertisements. At least as far as I'm concerned, I always change the TV channel when they start showing advertisement. But, I would try to answer this question by saying that different types of edibles are advertised such as juices, soft drinks, cookies, chips, cosmetic products et cetera. Moreover, especially in the last five years, technological products are also being promoted on TV advertisement. Some representative examples are smartphones, iPhone and laptops. Finally, cars constitute a category that is advertised a lot and there are many times that famous people like actors, singers and football players, are the main representative of those products."
  },
  {
    "id": 169,
    "Question_id": 470,
    "question": "Do you think that people pay attention to adverts on TV? Why do you think that is?",
    "answer": "As I mentioned earlier, most people do not pay that much attention to TV adverts. There are very few times when someone watches an advertisement because of the attractive theme of that advertisement. When a TV channel broadcasts advertisements, most people either change the channel or do other things. My opinion is that not every person is interested in every sort of advertisement. Another reason people pay less attention to TV adverts is that when watching a movie or a favourite programme, advertisements often bother them. Amid a lengthy programme, people need to take breaks and they mostly do that when advertisements are shown.  \n\nTips: Your answer could also be that people pay attention to TV adverts. If you say so, just clarify it with some examples. Try to say that those adverts are informative and present newly arrived products or services. They also inform us about the benefits of different products and let us chose our necessary goods among a great variety of options. Also, mention that ad creators use different innovative methods so that people watch it. Finally, say that people can hardly leave their seats while watching a live sports telecast or a favourite programme and when advertisements are shows, they intentionally and subconsciously watch them."
  },
  {
    "id": 170,
    "Question_id": 470,
    "question": "How important are regulations on TV advertising?",
    "answer": "I believe regulation on TV advertisements are of paramount importance. First of all, TV advertisements are displayed constantly all the time and the audiences come from different age groups. For that reason, the contents of an advertisement must be suitable for all audiences. In addition, every advertisement must be based on truth, moral code and sole purpose of informing people. Moreover, they should promote public health and not provide anything that might induce people to damage their health, such as tobacco and alcohol ads. Finally, the adverts should never exaggerate or falsify information about a product or service. To monitor the ethics, morality and regulation every advertisement should be censored before it is displayed on the TV."
  },
  {
    "id": 171,
    "Question_id": 521,
    "question": "Do you think laws are acceptable to the people? Why is that?",
    "answer": "I think that most people, by and large, are ready to accept any laws primarily because they are law-abiding citizens, and they respect the laws. Then, of course, some people accept the laws because they are “afraid” of the consequences of violating the laws. Besides, since most people are law-abiding citizens, because of the good education and upbringing they receive, they fully understand that without the rule of laws, anarchy, chaos and criminal behaviour will come to “consume” the entire society and country, which will keep nobody safe. Therefore, whether they like it or not, they accept the laws."
  },
  {
    "id": 172,
    "Question_id": 521,
    "question": "Is there any situation wherein people may disobey some laws? Why is so?",
    "answer": "Basically, there are two different kinds of situations wherein people may disobey the laws. First, if a situation comes when a person is not able to meet his/her basic needs, such as food and medicines, in order to survive, the chances are really high that he or she will disobey some laws, no matter how harsh the punishment is. Secondly, if a person feels that some laws are falling short of ensuring “justice” on a continuous basis, in the name of ensuring some “vague rule of laws”, it is only to be expected that people will disobey those laws. Interestingly, some people violate laws just because they do not know them or take the laws very lightly."
  },
  {
    "id": 173,
    "Question_id": 521,
    "question": "Do people like being a police officer in your country?Why/why not?",
    "answer": "No, I don’t really think that people in my country exactly like to become police officer primarily because they know that they won’t be able to do their jobs in a professional manner due to the political pressure from the top. They don’t like this police job also because police force in my country is way too much “stretched” and “ill-equipped” to deal with the regular law and order situations, let alone facing the bigger “security threats”. Finally, police forces in my country don’t exactly receive a good salary package, for the very demanding service they provide to their country, which would encourage the people to become a police officer."
  },
  {
    "id": 174,
    "Question_id": 521,
    "question": "What qualities should a good police officer possess?",
    "answer": "Just like any other professional, a police officer should also be honest, punctual, hard-working, well-educated, intelligent and helpful. However, in addition to those qualities, I just mentioned above, one has to be really tough, both physically and mentally, in order to maintain the law and order of the land effectively and efficiently, if someone wants to be considered a good police officer. Finally, one also has to be really patient, brave and “unbiased”, in order to become a good police officer, so that he can act “prudently” in a tricky security situation which threatens the lives of innocent people."
  },
  {
    "id": 175,
    "Question_id": 521,
    "question": "Should people be penalised when they use mobile phones while driving?",
    "answer": "Yes, I think that people should be “penalized” for using mobile phones while driving because this particular habit clearly threats the ‘road safety and security’ issues. In fact, according to the National Safety Council (USA), cell phone use, while driving, leads to 1.6 million crashes each year. Besides, nearly 390,000 injuries occur each year from accidents caused by texting while driving also. Finally, 1 out of every 4 car accidents in the United States is caused by texting and driving. Now, if these statistics are not enough to scare the “unruly” drivers, then the only thing left to do is to “punish or penalize” them for their dangerous habit of using mobile phones while driving."
  },
  {
    "id": 176,
    "Question_id": 521,
    "question": "What laws should be introduced so that people do not violate traffic rules? Why do you think so?",
    "answer": "Traffic laws that force people to pay hefty fines for violating traffic rules can be a good start. But, for serious violations, there should also be such laws that cancel the car registration, driving licenses and then take them to prison for a long term punishment. Finally, there should also be some provisions in the laws that will force the traffic rule violators to help the “injured and suffering persons” until they are ‘reasonably’ recovered from the wounds/damages of the accidents. I think that these kinds of laws will work to a large extent because they will make people pay “heavily” for their ‘irresponsible and criminal behaviour’."
  }
]